<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">First Aid</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="emergency_call">Emergency Call</string>
    <string name="immediate_actions_title">Immediate Actions:\n</string>
    <string name="search">Search</string>

    <string name="anaphylaxis_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A life-threatening allergic reaction (anaphylaxis) can cause shock, a sudden drop in blood pressure and trouble breathing. In people who have an allergy, anaphylaxis can occur minutes after exposure to a specific allergy-causing substance (allergen). In some cases, there may be a delayed reaction, or anaphylaxis may occur without an obvious trigger.</string>
    <string name="anaphylaxis_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Immediately call 911 or your local medical emergency number.\nAsk if the person is carrying an epinephrine autoinjector (EpiPen, Auvi-Q, others) to treat an allergic attack.\nIf the person needs to use an autoinjector, ask whether you should help inject the medication. This is usually done by pressing the autoinjector against the person\'s thigh.\nHave the person lie face up and be still.\nLoosen tight clothing and cover the person with a blanket. Don\'t give the person anything to drink.\nIf there\'s vomiting or bleeding from the mouth, turn the person to the side to prevent choking.\nIf there are no signs of breathing, coughing or movement, begin CPR. Do uninterrupted chest presses — about 100 every minute — until paramedics arrive.\nGet emergency treatment even if symptoms start to improve. After anaphylaxis, it\'s possible for symptoms to start again (recur). Monitoring in a hospital for several hours is usually necessary.\n</string>
    <string name="symptoms_title">Symptoms:\n</string>
    <string name="anaphylaxis_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Skin reactions, including hives, itching, and skin that becomes flushed or changes color\nSwelling of the face, eyes, lips or throat\nNarrowing of the airways, leading to wheezing and trouble breathing or swallowing\nA weak and rapid pulse\nNausea, vomiting or diarrhea\nDizziness, fainting or unconsciousness\n\nSome common anaphylaxis triggers include:\n\nMedications\nLatex\nFoods such as peanuts, tree nuts, fish and shellfish\nInsect stings from bees, yellow jackets, wasps, hornets and fire ants\n\nIf you\'ve had any kind of severe allergic reaction in the past, ask your doctor if you should be prescribed an epinephrine autoinjector to carry with you.</string>
    <string name="anaphylaxis_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Medications\nLatex\nFoods such as peanuts, tree nuts, fish and shellfish\nInsect stings from bees, yellow jackets, wasps, hornets and fire ants</string>
    <string name="anaphylaxis_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you\'re with someone having symptoms of anaphylaxis, don\'t wait to see whether symptoms get better. Seek emergency treatment right away. In severe cases, untreated anaphylaxis can lead to death within half an hour.\n\nAn antihistamine pill, such as diphenhydramine (Benadryl), isn\'t enough to treat anaphylaxis. These medications can help relieve allergy symptoms, but they work too slowly in a severe reaction.</string>
    <string name="anaphylaxis_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Immediately call 911 or your local medical emergency number.\nAsk if the person is carrying an epinephrine autoinjector (EpiPen, Auvi-Q, others) to treat an allergic attack.\nIf the person needs to use an autoinjector, ask whether you should help inject the medication. This is usually done by pressing the autoinjector against the person\'s thigh.\nHave the person lie face up and be still.\nLoosen tight clothing and cover the person with a blanket. Don\'t give the person anything to drink.\nIf there\'s vomiting or bleeding from the mouth, turn the person to the side to prevent choking.\nIf there are no signs of breathing, coughing or movement, begin CPR. Do uninterrupted chest presses — about 100 every minute — until paramedics arrive.\nGet emergency treatment even if symptoms start to improve. After anaphylaxis, it\'s possible for symptoms to start again (recur). Monitoring in a hospital for several hours is usually necessary.</string>
    <string name="anaphylaxis_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Anaphylaxis</string>


    <string name="AnimalBites_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Animal Bites</string>
    <string name="AnimalBites_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Bites sustained by an animal</string>
    <string name="AnimalBites_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To care for a minor animal bite or claw wound, such as one that only breaks the skin, take these steps:\n\nWash the wound thoroughly with soap and water.\nApply an antibiotic cream or ointment and cover the bite with a clean bandage.</string>
    <string name="AnimalBites_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Skin abrasions, etc.</string>
    <string name="AnimalBites_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek prompt medical care if:\nThe wound is a deep puncture or you\'re not sure how serious it is.\nThe skin is badly torn, crushed or bleeding significantly — first apply pressure with a bandage or clean cloth to stop the bleeding.\nYou notice increasing swelling, redness, pain or oozing, which are warning signs of infection.\nYou have questions about your risk of rabies or about rabies prevention. If the bite was caused by a cat or a dog, try to confirm that the animal\'s rabies vaccination is up to date. If the bite was caused by a wild animal, seek advice from your doctor about which animals are most likely to carry rabies.\n\nBats often carry rabies and can infect humans without leaving obvious signs of a bite. This is why the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommends that people in contact with bats — or even those who are sleeping and awaken to find a bat in the bedroom — seek medical advice about rabies shots, even if they don\'t think they\'ve been bitten.\n\nYou haven\'t had a tetanus shot in the past 10 years — or five years if the wound is deep or dirty. You may need a booster shot.</string>
    <string name="AnimalBites_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">None</string>
    <string name="AnimalBites_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Stay away from animals…</string>

    <string name="BlackEye_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Black Eye</string>
    <string name="BlackEye_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A black eye is bruising caused by bleeding in the tiny blood vessels in the skin surrounding the eye. Most injuries that cause a black eye aren\'t serious. But a black eye could be a sign of a more serious injury, such as an internal injury to the eye or a fracture of the thin bones around the eye. You may have a skull fracture if you have double vision, bruising around both eyes (raccoon eyes) or bleeding from the nose.</string>
    <string name="BlackEye_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Apply a cold compress soon after the injury. Using gentle pressure, place a cold pack, a cloth filled with ice — or even a bag of frozen vegetables — to the area around your eye. Take care not to press on the eye itself. Apply cold as soon as possible after the injury to reduce swelling. Repeat several times a day for a day or two.\nLook for blood. If you see blood in the white or colored parts of the eye, seek urgent care by an eye specialist (ophthalmologist).\nSeek medical care right away if you have vision problems, such as double vision or blurring. Also seek care right away if you have severe pain, bruising around both eyes, or bleeding in an eye or from the nose.</string>
    <string name="BlackEye_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">None</string>
    <string name="BlackEye_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Apply warm or hot compresses. This may be helpful after a few days when the swelling has gone down. Repeat several times a day for a day or two.</string>
    <string name="BlackEye_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">None</string>
    <string name="BlackEye_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">None</string>

    <string name="Blisters_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Blisters</string>
    <string name="Blisters_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A blister is a painful skin condition where fluid fills a space between layers of skin. They form when something — like too-tight shoes — repeatedly rubs against your skin. These fluid-filled bubbles are a pain, but you can treat them easily at home.</string>
    <string name="Blisters_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If a blister isn\'t too painful, try to keep it intact. Unbroken skin over a blister may provide a natural barrier to bacteria and decreases the risk of infection. Cover it with a bandage or moleskin. Cut a piece of moleskin into a doughnut shape and place the pad so that it encircles and protects the blister. Then cover the blister and moleskin with gauze.\n\nSeek medical care if the blister looks infected. If you have diabetes or poor circulation, call your doctor before treating the blister yourself.</string>
    <string name="Blisters_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Blister</string>
    <string name="Blisters_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">You can get blisters in several different ways, including some diseases. The most common types of blisters include:\n\nBlood blisters: You can get blood blisters when something pinches your skin. Instead of clear liquid, blood floods the area from broken blood vessels and damage to the lower layers of the skin. The blood pools and forms a blister.\nFriction blisters: Caused by rubbing on the skin, friction blisters form when clear fluid builds up in the upper layers of skin. Many people get friction blisters from walking too much in poor-fitting shoes or by not wearing socks. You can also get them on your hands from holding things like shovels or other tools.\nHeat blisters: You can get these blisters from burns or sunburns. They may also form after you warm up from frostbite. Blistering skin is part of a second-degree burn.</string>
    <string name="Blisters_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To relieve blister-related pain, drain the fluid while leaving the overlying skin intact. Here\'s how:\n\nWash your hands and the blister with soap and warm water.\nSwab the blister with iodine.\nClean a sharp needle with rubbing alcohol.\nUse the needle to prick the blister in several spots near the edge. Let the fluid drain, but leave the overlying skin in place.\nApply an ointment such as petroleum jelly to the blister and cover it with a nonstick gauze bandage. If a rash appears, stop using the ointment.\nFollow-up care. Check the area every day for infection. After several days, use a tweezers and scissors sterilized with rubbing alcohol to cut away the dead skin. Apply more ointment and a bandage.</string>
    <string name="Blisters_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To prevent friction blisters on your feet, wear shoes that fit well. It also helps to use moisture-wicking socks. Try the various socks, shoes and insoles that are designed specifically to help reduce blistering. You might also try attaching moleskin to the inside of your shoes where it might rub. Or you can dust the inside of your socks with foot powder. Gloves help prevent blisters on your hands.</string>

    <string name="Bruise_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Bruise</string>
    <string name="Bruise_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A bruise forms when blood vessels under the skin break. The trapped blood creates a bruise that\'s black, purple or blue then changes color as it heals.</string>
    <string name="Bruise_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">None</string>
    <string name="Bruise_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">None</string>
    <string name="Bruise_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">None</string>
    <string name="Bruise_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">You can enhance bruise healing with a few simple techniques.\n\nElevate the bruised area above heart level, if possible.\nApply an ice pack wrapped in a thin towel. Leave it in place for 20 minutes. Repeat several times for a day or two after the injury. This helps to reduce the swelling and pain.\nIf the bruised area is swelling, put an elastic bandage around it, but not too tight.\nIf the skin isn\'t broken, you don\'t need to bandage a bruise. Consider taking a nonprescription pain reliever if needed.</string>
    <string name="Bruise_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Consult a healthcare professional if you:\nHave very painful swelling in the bruised area.\nSuspect a bruise has been caused by child abuse, domestic violence or elder abuse.\nStill have pain three days after a minor injury.\nHave frequent, large or painful bruises.\nHave bruises that begin suddenly or seem to develop for no reason.\nHave a personal or family history of easy bruising or bleeding.\nNotice a lump form over the bruise, which may be a sign of pooling blood, also called a hematoma.\nHave unusual bleeding, such as from the nose or gums.</string>

    <string name="Burns_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Burns</string>
    <string name="Burns_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Burns are tissue damage from hot liquids, the sun, flames, chemicals, electricity, steam and other causes. Kitchen-related injuries from hot drinks, soups and microwaved foods are common among children.\n\nMajor burns need emergency medical help. Minor burns can usually be treated with first aid.\n\n</string>
    <string name="Burns_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call 911 or seek immediate care for major burns, which:\n\nAre deep, involving all layers of the skin\nCause the skin to be dry and leathery\nMay appear charred or have patches of white, brown or black\nAre larger than 3 inches (about 8 centimeters) in diameter\nCover the hands, feet, face, groin, buttocks or a major joint, or encircles an arm or leg\nAre accompanied by smoke inhalation\nBegin swelling very quickly\nElectrical burns, including those caused by lightning, and major chemical burns need emergency medical care. A minor burn might need emergency care if it affects the eyes, mouth, hands or genital areas. Babies and older adults might need emergency care for minor burns as well.</string>
    <string name="Burns_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Major vs. Minor burns distinguished below:</string>
    <string name="Burns_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Burns_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Treating major burns\nUntil emergency help arrives:\n\nProtect the burned person from further harm. If you can do so safely, make sure the person you\'re helping is not in contact with the source of the burn. For electrical burns, make sure the power source is off before you approach the burned person. Don\'t try to remove clothing stuck in the burn.\nMake certain that the person burned is breathing. If needed, begin rescue breathing if you know how.\nRemove jewelry, belts and other tight items, especially from the burned area and the neck. Burned areas swell quickly.\nCover the burn. Loosely cover the area with gauze or a clean cloth.\nRaise the burned area. Lift the wound above heart level if possible.\nWatch for signs of shock. Signs and symptoms include cool, clammy skin, weak pulse and shallow breathing.\nTreating minor burns\nFor minor burns:\n\nCool the burn. Hold the area under cool (not cold) running water for about 10 minutes. If the burn is on the face, apply a cool, wet cloth until the pain eases. For a mouth burn from hot food or drink, put a piece of ice in the mouth for a few minutes.\nRemove rings or other tight items from the burned area. Try to do this quickly and gently, before the area swells.\nDon\'t break blisters. Blisters help protect against infection. If a blister does break, gently clean the area with water and apply an antibiotic ointment.\nApply lotion. After the burn is cooled, apply a lotion, such as one with aloe vera or cocoa butter. This helps prevent drying and provides relief.\nBandage the burn. Cover the burn with a clean bandage. Wrap it loosely to avoid putting pressure on burned skin. Bandaging keeps air off the area, reduces pain and protects blistered skin.\nIf needed, take a nonprescription pain reliever, such as ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others), naproxen sodium (Aleve) or acetaminophen (Tylenol, others).</string>
    <string name="Burns_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="ChemicalBurns_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Chemical burns are tissue damage caused by strong acids, drain cleaners, paint thinner, gasoline and many other substances. Usually, you are aware of such a burn and its cause. But sometimes you may not immediately recognize a burn caused by a milder chemical. As with some sunburns, the damage may develop hours after the exposure. Major chemical burns need emergency medical help. Minor chemical burn can usually be treated with first aid.</string>
    <string name="ChemicalBurns_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Chemical Burns</string>
    <string name="ChemicalBurns_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call 911 or seek immediate care for major chemical burns, which:\n\nAre deep, involving all layers of the skin\nAre larger than 3 inches (about 8 centimeters) in diameter\nCover the hands, feet, face, groin, buttocks, or a major joint or encircles an arm or leg\nMight cause shock, with symptoms such as cool, clammy skin, weak pulse and shallow breathing.\nIf you\'re unsure you\'ve been exposed to a toxic chemical, call a poison control center then call 911. There are two ways to get help from Poison Control in the United States: online at www.poison.org or by calling 800–222–1222. Both options are free, confidential and available 24 hours a day. If you seek emergency medical help, take the container or the name of the chemical with you.</string>
    <string name="ChemicalBurns_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ChemicalBurns_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ChemicalBurns_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you think you have a chemical burn, take these steps immediately:\n\nRemove dry chemicals. Put on gloves and brush off any remaining material.\nRemove contaminated clothing or jewelry and rinse chemicals off for at least 20 minutes, in a shower if it\'s available. Protect your eyes from chemical contamination.\nBandage the burn. Cover the burn with a clean bandage. Wrap it loosely to avoid putting pressure on burned skin.\nRinse again if needed. If you feel more burning, rinse the area again for several more minutes.</string>
    <string name="ChemicalBurns_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="ChemicalEyeSplash_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Chemical splash in the eye</string>
    <string name="ChemicalEyeSplash_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ChemicalEyeSplash_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If a chemical splashes into your eye, take these steps immediately.\n\nFlush your eye with water. Use clean, lukewarm tap water for at least 20 minutes. Use whichever of these approaches is quickest:\nGet into the shower and aim a gentle stream of water on your forehead over your affected eye. Or direct the stream on the bridge of your nose if both eyes are affected. Hold the lids of your affected eye or eyes open.\nPut your head down and turn it to the side. Then hold the lids of your affected eye open under a gently running faucet. If you have access to a work site eye-rinse station, use it.\nYoung children may do best if they lie down in the bathtub or lean back over a sink. Pour a gentle stream of water on the forehead over the affected eye or on the bridge of the nose to flush both eyes.\nWash your hands with soap and water. Thoroughly rinse your hands to be sure no chemical or soap is left on them.\nRemove contact lenses. If they don\'t come out during the flush, then take them out.\n</string>
    <string name="ChemicalEyeSplash_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ChemicalEyeSplash_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ChemicalEyeSplash_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Caution\nDon\'t rub the eye — this may cause further damage.\nDon\'t put anything except water or contact lens saline rinse in the eye. And don\'t use eyedrops unless emergency personnel tell you to do so.\nSeek emergency medical assistance\nAfter following the above steps, seek emergency care by an eye specialist (ophthalmologist) or call 911 or your local emergency number. Take the chemical container or the name of the chemical with you to the emergency provider. If readily available, wear sunglasses to help reduce sensitivity to light.</string>
    <string name="ChemicalEyeSplash_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="ChestPain_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Chest Pain</string>
    <string name="ChestPain_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">First aid for chest pain depends on the cause. Causes of chest pain can vary. Serious health conditions such as a heart attack or blood clot in the lungs can cause chest pain. Other causes of chest pain include heartburn, pulled muscles and emotional stress.\n\nIt can be difficult to tell if chest pain is due to a heart attack or other health condition, especially if you\'ve never had chest pain before. Don\'t try to diagnose the cause yourself. Get emergency medical help if you have unexplained chest pain that lasts more than a few minutes.\n\nHeart attack\nA heart attack generally causes chest pain for more than 15 minutes. The pain may be mild or severe. Some heart attacks happen suddenly. But sometimes warning symptoms happen hours or days in advance.\n\nAngina\nAngina is chest pain or discomfort caused by reduced blood flow to the heart. It\'s relatively common. But it can be hard to tell it apart from other types of chest pain, such as indigestion.\n\nPulmonary embolism\nPulmonary embolism is a blood clot in the lung. It happens when a clot, usually in the leg or pelvis, breaks free and gets stuck in a lung artery. The clot blocks or reduces blood flow. This makes it harder for the lungs to send oxygen to the rest of the body.\n\nAortic dissection\nAn aortic dissection is a tear in the inner layer of the body\'s main artery, called the aorta. Aortic dissection is a life-threatening condition that needs emergency medical treatment.\n\nPneumonia with pleurisy\nPneumonia is an infection of the air sacs in the lungs. Symptoms include chest pain, chills, fever, and a cough that may produce bloody or foul-smelling sputum. Pleurisy is inflammation of the tissues that surround the lung. It can cause chest pain when taking a breath or coughing.\n\nUnlike a true heart attack, pleurisy pain is usually relieved temporarily by holding your breath or putting pressure on the painful area of your chest.\n\nIf you\'ve recently been diagnosed with pneumonia and have symptoms of pleurisy, see a healthcare professional. Pleurisy alone isn\'t a medical emergency, but you shouldn\'t try to make the diagnosis yourself.\n\nPericarditis\nPericarditis is swelling and irritation of the thin, saclike tissue surrounding your heart. It causes sharp chest pain. The chest pain gets worse when you cough, lie down or take a deep breath.\n\nPericarditis is usually mild and goes away without treatment. If it\'s severe, you may need medicine or, rarely, surgery.\n\nIt may be hard to tell the difference between sudden pericarditis and pain due to a heart attack. If you have sudden, unexplained chest pain, seek emergency medical help.\n\nChest wall pain\nChest wall pain is a type of muscle pain. Bruised chest muscles may happen from excessive coughing, straining or a minor injury.\n\nOne type of chest wall pain is costochondritis. Costochondritis causes pain and tenderness in and around the cartilage that connects the ribs to the breastbone.\n\nIf you have costochondritis, pressing on a few points along the edge of your breastbone often triggers considerable tenderness. If gently touching the area with your fingers causes chest pain, it\'s unlikely that a serious condition, such as a heart attack, is the cause.</string>
    <string name="ChestPain_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you or someone else may be having a heart attack, follow these first-aid steps:\nCall 911 or emergency medical help. Don\'t ignore the symptoms of a heart attack. If an ambulance or emergency vehicle can\'t come to you, have someone drive you to the nearest hospital. Drive yourself only if there are no other options.\nTake aspirin, if recommended. Aspirin helps prevent blood clotting. Taking aspirin during a heart attack may reduce heart damage. Don\'t take an aspirin unless a healthcare professional says to do so. Don\'t delay calling 911 to take an aspirin. Call for emergency help first.\nTake nitroglycerin, if prescribed. If you think you\'re having a heart attack and your healthcare professional has previously prescribed nitroglycerin for you, take it as directed. Don\'t take anyone else\'s nitroglycerin.\nStart CPR if the person doesn\'t have a pulse or isn\'t breathing. If you\'re untrained in CPR, do hands-only CPR. That means push hard and fast on the person\'s chest about 100 to 120 times a minute. If you\'re trained in CPR and confident in your ability, start with 30 chest compressions before giving two rescue breaths.\nUse an automated external defibrillator (AED) if one is immediately available and the person is unconscious. The device sends shocks to the heart to reset the heart rhythm. AEDs come with step-by-step voice instructions for their use. They only give a shock when appropriate.</string>
    <string name="ChestPain_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heart attack:\nChest pain that may feel like pressure, tightness, pain, squeezing or aching.\nPain or discomfort that spreads to the shoulder, arm, back, neck, jaw, teeth or sometimes the upper belly.\nCold sweat.\nFatigue.\nHeartburn or indigestion.\nLightheadedness or sudden dizziness.\nNausea.\nShortness of breath.\n\nAngina:\nAngina may feel like squeezing, pressure, heaviness, tightness or pain in the chest. It can be stable or unstable.\n\nStable angina usually happens during activity and goes away with rest or angina medicine. The pain is predictable and usually similar to previous bouts of chest pain. The chest pain typically lasts a short time, perhaps five minutes or less.\nUnstable angina is unpredictable and occurs at rest. Or the angina pain is worsening and occurs with less activity. It doesn\'t go away with rest or the medicine. Unstable angina is dangerous and needs emergency treatment. It may be a sign of a future heart attack.\n\nPulmonary embolism:\nSymptoms of pulmonary embolism may include:\n\nSudden, sharp chest pain often with shortness of breath.\nSudden, unexplained shortness of breath, even without pain.\nCough that may produce blood-streaked spit.\nRapid heartbeat with shortness of breath.\nFainting.\nSevere anxiety.\nUnexplained sweating.\nSwelling of one leg only, caused by a blood clot in the leg.\n\nAortic dissection:\nSudden severe chest or upper back pain, often described as a tearing or ripping sensation, that spreads to the neck or down the back.\nSudden severe stomach pain.\nLoss of consciousness.\nShortness of breath.\nStroke symptoms such as sudden vision problems, difficulty speaking, and weakness or loss of movement on one side of your body.\nWeak pulse in one arm or thigh compared with the other.\nLeg pain.\nDifficulty walking.</string>
    <string name="ChestPain_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ChestPain_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">When to see a healthcare professional\nChest pain is a common reason that people seek medical treatment. Anxiety, indigestion, infection, muscle strain, and heart or lung disease can all cause chest pain.\n\nIf you have new or unexplained chest pain, see a healthcare professional. If you think you\'re having a heart attack, call 911 or your local emergency number. Don\'t try to diagnose the chest pain yourself or ignore it. Treatment depends on the specific cause of the pain.</string>
    <string name="ChestPain_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Anxiety, indigestion, infection, muscle strain, and heart or lung disease can all cause chest pain.\n\n</string>

    <string name="CornealAbrasion_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Corneal Abrasion (scratch)</string>
    <string name="CornealAbrasion_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A corneal abrasion is a superficial scratch on the clear, protective \"window\" at the front of the eye (cornea). The cornea can be scratched by contact with dust, dirt, sand, wood shavings, plant matter, metal particles, contact lenses or even the edge of a piece of paper.</string>
    <string name="CornealAbrasion_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">In case of a corneal abrasion, seek prompt medical attention. Left untreated, the abrasion could become infected and result in a sore known as a corneal ulcer. In the meantime, take these immediate steps:\n\nRinse your eye with clean water or a saline solution. You can use an eyecup or a small, clean drinking glass positioned with its rim resting on the bone at the base of your eye socket. If you have quick access to a work site eye-rinse station, use it. Rinsing the eye may wash out a foreign object.\nBlink several times. This may remove small particles.\nPull the upper eyelid over the lower eyelid. This may cause your eye to tear, which may help wash out the particle. Or it may cause the lashes of your lower eyelid to brush away an object from under your upper eyelid.\nUse the following pointers to avoid making the injury worse:\n\nDon\'t try to remove an object that is embedded in your eye or makes your eye difficult to close.\nDon\'t rub your eye after an injury.\nDon\'t touch your eye with cotton swabs, tweezers or other instruments.\nIf you use contact lenses, don\'t wear them while your eye is healing.</string>
    <string name="CornealAbrasion_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Pain\nBlurry vision\nA gritty feeling in the eye\nTearing\nRedness\nSensitivity to the light (photophobia)\nHeadache</string>
    <string name="CornealAbrasion_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">" The cornea can be scratched by contact with dust, dirt, sand, wood shavings, plant matter, metal particles, contact lenses or even the edge of a piece of paper."</string>
    <string name="CornealAbrasion_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Most corneal abrasions heal in a few days but should be treated with antibiotic drops or ointment to reduce the risk of infection.</string>
    <string name="CornealAbrasion_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="CutsScrapes_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Cuts and Scrapes</string>
    <string name="CutsScrapes_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="CutsScrapes_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Wash your hands. This helps avoid infection.\nStop the bleeding. Minor cuts and scrapes usually stop bleeding on their own. If needed, gently press the wound with a clean bandage or cloth. Raise the area until the bleeding stops.\nClean the wound. Rinse the wound with water. Keeping the wound under running water will lower the risk of infection. Wash around the wound with soap. But don\'t get soap in the wound. And don\'t use hydrogen peroxide or iodine. Both can irritate wounds. Remove any dirt or debris with tweezers cleaned with alcohol. See a healthcare professional if you can\'t remove all debris.\nPut on an antibiotic or petroleum jelly. Put on a thin layer of an antibiotic ointment or petroleum jelly to keep the surface moist and help prevent scarring. Ingredients in some antibiotic ointments can cause a mild rash in some people. If you get a rash, stop using the ointment.\nCover the wound. Put on a bandage, rolled gauze or gauze held in place with paper tape. Covering the wound keeps it clean. If you have just a minor scrape or scratch, don\'t cover it.\nChange the covering. Do this at least once a day or whenever the covering becomes wet or dirty.\nGet a tetanus shot. Get a tetanus shot if you haven\'t had one in the past five years and the wound is deep or dirty.\nWatch for signs of infection. See a healthcare professional if you see signs of infection on the skin or near the wound. These include expanding changes in color, increasing pain, drainage, warmth or swelling.</string>
    <string name="CutsScrapes_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="CutsScrapes_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="CutsScrapes_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="CutsScrapes_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="Dislocation_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A dislocation is an injury that forces the bones in a joint out of position. The cause is usually a fall, a car accident or an injury during contact sports.\n\nDislocation mostly involves the body\'s larger joints. The most common site of injury is the shoulder. For young children, the elbow is a common site. Smaller joints, such as the thumbs and fingers, also can be dislocated if bent the wrong way with force.</string>
    <string name="Dislocation_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Dislocation</string>
    <string name="Dislocation_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">The injury will deform the joint and make it hard to move. Dislocation might cause sudden and severe pain and swelling. A dislocation needs prompt medical attention to put the bones back in place.\n</string>
    <string name="Dislocation_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Don\'t put off medical care. Get medical help as soon as you can.\nDon\'t move the joint. Until you get help, use a splint to keep the affected joint from moving. Don\'t try to move a dislocated joint or force it back into place. This can damage the joint and the muscles, ligaments, nerves or blood vessels around it.\nPut ice on the injured joint. This can help reduce swelling. Ice can control bleeding inside the body and keep fluids from building up in and around the injured joint</string>
    <string name="Dislocation_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">See medical care</string>
    <string name="Dislocation_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Dislocation_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="ElectricalBurns_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Electrical Burns</string>
    <string name="ElectricalBurns_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Electrical burns may be caused by a number of sources of electricity. Examples include lightning, stun guns, and contact with job site or household current.\n\nMinor electrical skin burns are treated like any other minor burn. Put a cool wet cloth on the area. Do not break any blisters. After you gently clean the skin, put a bandage on the area. If you have any questions about how severe the burn is, contact a health care provider.</string>
    <string name="ElectricalBurns_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Take these actions immediately while waiting for medical help:\n\nTurn off the source of electricity if possible. If not, move the source away from both you and the injured person. Use a dry, nonconducting object made of cardboard, plastic or wood.\nBegin CPR if the person is not breathing, coughing or moving and doesn\'t have a pulse.\nDo not remove clothing or try to clean the burned area. Cover any burned areas with a sterile gauze bandage, if available, or a clean cloth or sheet. Don\'t use a blanket or towel, because fuzz or loose fibers can stick to the burns.\nTry to prevent the injured person from becoming chilled.</string>
    <string name="ElectricalBurns_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call 911 or your local emergency number if the injured person experiences:\n\nSevere burns\nConfusion\nDifficulty breathing\nIrregular heart rhythm (arrhythmias)\nDoes not have a pulse and is not breathing (cardiac arrest)\nMuscle pain and contractions\nSeizures\nLoss of consciousness</string>
    <string name="ElectricalBurns_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ElectricalBurns_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A person who has been injured by contact with electricity should be seen by a health care provider. The damage may be worse than it looks from the burn on the skin. Sometimes an electrical injury can cause damage to skin, muscles, blood vessels and nerves, often in an arm or a leg. The heart, brain and other body organs can be damaged.\n\nCaution\nDon\'t touch the injured person if the person is still in contact with the electrical current.\nCall 911 or your local emergency number if the source of the burn is a high-voltage wire or lightning. Don\'t get near high-voltage wires until the power is turned off. Overhead power lines usually aren\'t insulated. Stay at least 50 feet (about 15 meters) away — farther if wires are jumping and sparking.\nDon\'t drive over downed power lines. If a live electrical line contacts the vehicle you\'re in, stay in the vehicle. Call 911 or your local emergency number to disable the power line before touching any metal to try to exit the vehicle.\nDon\'t move a person with an electrical injury unless the person is in immediate danger.</string>
    <string name="ElectricalBurns_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="ElectricalShock_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Electrical Shock</string>
    <string name="ElectricalShock_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">The danger from an electrical shock depends on the type of current, how high the voltage is, how the current traveled through the body, the person\'s overall health and how quickly the person is treated.\n\nAn electrical shock may cause burns, or it may leave no visible mark on the skin. In either case, an electrical current passing through the body can cause damage inside the body, cardiac arrest or other injury. Under certain circumstances, even a small amount of electricity can be fatal.</string>
    <string name="ElectricalShock_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Take these actions immediately while waiting for medical help:\n\nTurn off the source of electricity, if possible. If not, use a dry, nonconducting object made of cardboard, plastic or wood to move the source away from you and the injured person.\nBegin CPR if the person shows no signs of circulation, such as breathing, coughing or movement.\nTry to prevent the injured person from becoming chilled.\nApply a bandage. Cover any burned areas with a sterile gauze bandage, if available, or a clean cloth. Don\'t use a blanket or towel, because loose fibers can stick to the burns.</string>
    <string name="ElectricalShock_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call 911 or your local emergency number if the injured person experiences:\n\nSevere burns\nConfusion\nDifficulty breathing\nHeart rhythm problems\nCardiac arrest\nMuscle pain and contractions\nSeizures\nLoss of consciousness</string>
    <string name="ElectricalShock_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ElectricalShock_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A person who has been injured by contact with electricity should be seen by a health care provider.\n\nCaution\nDon\'t touch an injured person who is still in contact with an electrical current.\nCall 911 or your local emergency number if the source of the burn is a high-voltage wire or lightning. Don\'t get near high-voltage wires until the power is turned off. Overhead power lines usually aren\'t insulated. Stay at least 20 feet (about 6 meters) away — farther if wires are jumping and sparking.\nDon\'t move a person with an electrical injury unless there is immediate danger.</string>
    <string name="ElectricalShock_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="Fainting_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Fainting</string>
    <string name="Fainting_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Fainting occurs when the brain doesn\'t receive enough blood for a brief time. This causes loss of consciousness. Consciousness is usually regained quickly.\n\nFainting might have no medical significance. Or the cause can be a serious disorder, occasionally involving the heart. Therefore, treat loss of consciousness as a medical emergency until the symptoms are relieved and the cause is known. Talk to your health care provider if you faint more than once.</string>
    <string name="Fainting_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you feel faint\nLie down or sit down. To reduce the chance of fainting again, don\'t get up too quickly.\nPlace your head between your knees if you sit down.\nIf someone else faints\nPosition the person on the back. If there are no injuries and the person is breathing, raise the person\'s legs above heart level if possible. Prop up the person\'s legs about 12 inches (30 centimeters). Loosen belts, collars or other tight clothing.\n\nTo reduce the chance of fainting again, don\'t get the person up too fast. If the person doesn\'t regain consciousness within one minute, call 911 or your local emergency number.\n\nCheck for breathing. Check for a pulse and to see if the person is breathing. If the person is not breathing, begin CPR. Call 911 or your local emergency number. Continue CPR until help arrives or the person begins to breathe.\nIf the person was injured in a fall associated with a faint, treat bumps, bruises or cuts appropriately. Control bleeding with direct pressure.</string>
    <string name="Fainting_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Fainting_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Fainting occurs when the brain doesn\'t receive enough blood for a brief time. This causes loss of consciousness. Consciousness is usually regained quickly.\n\nFainting might have no medical significance. Or the cause can be a serious disorder, occasionally involving the heart. Therefore, treat loss of consciousness as a medical emergency until the symptoms are relieved and the cause is known.</string>
    <string name="Fainting_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you feel faint\nLie down or sit down. To reduce the chance of fainting again, don\'t get up too quickly.\nPlace your head between your knees if you sit down.\nIf someone else faints\nPosition the person on the back. If there are no injuries and the person is breathing, raise the person\'s legs above heart level if possible. Prop up the person\'s legs about 12 inches (30 centimeters). Loosen belts, collars or other tight clothing.\n\nTo reduce the chance of fainting again, don\'t get the person up too fast. If the person doesn\'t regain consciousness within one minute, call 911 or your local emergency number.\n\nCheck for breathing. Check for a pulse and to see if the person is breathing. If the person is not breathing, begin CPR. Call 911 or your local emergency number. Continue CPR until help arrives or the person begins to breathe.</string>
    <string name="Fainting_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To reduce the chance of fainting again, don\'t get the person up too fast. If the person doesn\'t regain consciousness within one minute, call 911 or your local emergency number.</string>


    <string name="Fever_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Fever</string>
    <string name="Fever_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A fever is a rise in body temperature. It\'s usually a sign of infection. The fever itself is generally harmless and probably helpful. Fevers usually don\'t need treatment.\n\nThe average body temperature is 98.6 F (37 C). But normal body temperature can range between 97 F (36.1 C) and 99 F (37.2 C) or more. Your body temperature can vary depending on how active you are or the time of day. Generally, older people have lower body temperatures than younger people have.\n\nThe following thermometer readings generally indicate a fever:\n\nRectal, ear or temporal artery temperature of 100.4 (38 C) or higher\nOral temperature of 100 F (37.8 C) or higher\nArmpit temperature of 99 F (37.2 C) or higher</string>
    <string name="Fever_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Adults with fevers of 103 F (39.4 C) or higher will generally look and act sick. The main goal of treatment is to relieve discomfort and help you get rest.\nChildren with relatively high fevers may not look or act particularly sick. Treating a fever depends on the degree of discomfort. If your child is uncomfortable or restless, these home care strategies may help:</string>
    <string name="Fever_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">When to seek medical advice for an adult\nSeek medical care if someone with a fever has any of the following signs and symptoms:\n\nDifficulty breathing\nChest pain\nSevere headache\nConfusion or agitation\nAbdominal pain\nRepeated vomiting\nDry mouth, decreased or dark urine, or refusal to drink fluids, which may indicate dehydration\nSkin rashes\nDifficulty swallowing fluids\nPain with urination or pain in the back\n\nWhen to seek medical advice for a child\nIf your baby is less than 3 months old and has a fever, it\'s important to get medical help immediately.\n\nSeek medical care if a child of any age shows any of the following:\n\nFussiness, or acting abnormally, which doesn\'t improve even after taking medications to bring down the fever\nSigns and symptoms of dehydration, such as no wet diapers over eight to 10 hours, crying without tears, a dry mouth or refusing to drink any fluids\nStiff neck or a headache\nAbdominal pain\nTrouble breathing\nRash\nJoint pain or swelling\nAlso get medical help if the fever lasts more than five days in a row.\n\nWhen to seek emergency care\nSeek emergency medical care if your child has a fever after being left in a hot car or involved in another such potentially dangerous situation and shows any of these warning signs:\n\nFever with no sweating\nSevere headache\nSeizures\nStiff neck\nConfusion\nRepeated vomiting or diarrhea\nIrritability or significant discomfort\nAny worrisome, different or unusual symptoms</string>
    <string name="Fever_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A fever is a rise in body temperature. It\'s usually a sign of infection. The fever itself is generally harmless and probably helpful. Fevers usually don\'t need treatment.</string>
    <string name="Fever_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Treating fever in an adult\nAdults with fevers of 103 F (39.4 C) or higher will generally look and act sick. The main goal of treatment is to relieve discomfort and help you get rest.\n\nTo treat a fever at home:\n\nDrink plenty of fluids to stay hydrated.\nDress in lightweight clothing.\nUse a light blanket if you feel chilled, until the chills end.\nTake acetaminophen (Tylenol, others) or ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others). Follow the directions on the label.\n\n\n\n\nTreating fever in a child\nChildren with relatively high fevers may not look or act particularly sick. Treating a fever depends on the degree of discomfort. If your child is uncomfortable or restless, these home care strategies may help:\n\nEncourage your child to drink fluids\nDress your child in lightweight clothing.\nUse a light blanket if your child feels chilled, until the chills end.\nDon\'t give aspirin to children or teenagers.\nDon\'t give an infant any type of pain reliever until after you\'ve contacted a doctor and your child has been evaluated.\nIf your child is 6 months old or older, give your child acetaminophen (Tylenol, others) or ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin, others). Read the label carefully for proper dosing.</string>
    <string name="Fever_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">How to take a temperature\nAlways use a digital thermometer to check someone\'s temperature. Various types are available:\n\nRectal thermometers are used in the rectum.\nOral thermometers are used in the mouth.\nTemporal artery thermometers use an infrared scanner to measure the temperature of the temporal artery in the forehead.\nArmpit (axillary) and ear (tympanic membrane) thermometers, which are less accurate.\nBecause of the potential for mercury exposure or ingestion, glass mercury thermometers have been phased out and are no longer recommended.\n\nNo matter which type of thermometer you use, take these precautions when using it:\n\nRead the instructions that came with the thermometer.\nClean the thermometer before and after each use with rubbing alcohol or soap and lukewarm water.\nDon\'t use the same thermometer for both oral and rectal temperatures. Get two and label which is used where.\nNever leave a child unattended while taking his or her temperature.\nRectal temperature (for infants)\nTurn on the digital thermometer and dab petroleum jelly or another lubricant on the tip of the thermometer.\nLay the child on his or her stomach or side, with knees flexed.\nCarefully insert the tip ½ to 1 inch (1.3 to 2.5 centimeters) into the rectum.\nHold the thermometer and child still until the thermometer beep indicates it\'s done. To avoid injury, don\'t let go of the thermometer while it\'s inside the child.\nRemove the thermometer and read the number.\nOral temperature\nTurn on the digital thermometer. Place the thermometer tip under the tongue.\nClose the mouth around the thermometer for the recommended amount of time or until the thermometer beep indicates it\'s done.\nRemove the thermometer and read the number.\nTemporal artery temperature\nTurn on the digital thermometer. Gently sweep it across the forehead and read the number.\nArmpit temperature\nTurn on the digital thermometer. Place the thermometer under the armpit, making sure it touches skin, not clothing.\nHold the thermometer tightly in place until you hear the thermometer beep indicating it\'s done.\nRemove the thermometer and read the number.\nEar temperature\nTurn on the digital thermometer. Gently place it in the ear canal no further than indicated by the instructions that came with the device.\nHold the thermometer tightly in place until you hear the thermometer beep indicating it\'s done.\nRemove the thermometer and read the number.</string>


    <string name="FoodborneIllness_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Foodborne Illness</string>
    <string name="FoodborneIllness_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">All foods naturally contain small amounts of bacteria. But improper handling, cooking or storage of food can result in bacteria multiplying in large enough numbers to cause illness. Parasites, viruses, toxins and chemicals also can contaminate food and cause illness.</string>
    <string name="FoodborneIllness_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Foodborne illness often improves on its own within a few days.\n\nCall your doctor if:\n\nVomiting persists for more than two days\nDiarrhea persists for more than several days\nDiarrhea turns bloody, black or tarry\nFever is 101 F (38.3 C) or higher\nLightheadedness or fainting occurs with standing\nConfusion develops\nWorrisome abdominal pain develops\nSeek emergency medical assistance if:\n\nYou have severe symptoms, such as severe abdominal pain or watery diarrhea that turns very bloody within 24 hours.\nYou belong to a high-risk group.\nYou suspect botulism poisoning. Botulism is a potentially fatal food poisoning that results from the ingestion of a toxin formed by certain spores in food. Botulism toxin is most often found in home-canned foods, especially green beans or tomatoes.</string>
    <string name="FoodborneIllness_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Symptoms of food poisoning vary with the source of contamination. Generally they include:\n\nDiarrhea, which may be bloody\nNausea\nAbdominal pain\nVomiting\nDehydration\nLow-grade fever (sometimes)\nIf you are very dehydrated, you might notice:\n\nFeeling lightheaded or faint, especially when you stand up\nFatigue\nDark-colored urine\nLess frequent urination\nExcessive thirst\nWhether you become ill after eating contaminated food depends on the organism, the amount of exposure, your age and your health.\n\nHigh-risk groups include:\n\nOlder adults. As you get older, your immune system may not respond as quickly and as effectively to infectious organisms as it once did.\nInfants and young children. Their immune systems haven\'t fully developed.\nPeople with chronic diseases. Having a chronic condition, such as diabetes or AIDS, or receiving chemotherapy or radiation therapy for cancer, reduces your immune response.\nPregnant people. Pregnancy alters your immune system, making it harder to fight off infections that may affect you and your developing baby.</string>
    <string name="FoodborneIllness_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Sip liquids, such as a sports drink or water, to prevent dehydration. Drinking fluids too quickly can worsen nausea and vomiting, so try to take small frequent sips over a couple of hours instead of drinking a large amount at once.\nTake note of urination. You should be urinating at regular intervals, and your urine should be light and clear. Infrequent passage of dark urine is a sign of dehydration. Dizziness and lightheadedness also are symptoms of dehydration. If any of these symptoms occur and you can\'t drink enough fluids, seek medical attention.\nAvoid anti-diarrheal medications. They may slow your body\'s removal of organisms or toxins from your system. If in doubt, check with your doctor about your particular situation.</string>
    <string name="FoodborneIllness_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Symptoms of botulism usually begin 12 to 36 hours after eating the contaminated food and may include headache, blurred vision, muscle weakness and eventual paralysis. Some people also have nausea and vomiting, constipation, urinary retention, difficulty breathing, and a dry mouth. These symptoms require immediate medical attention.</string>
    <string name="FoodborneIllness_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Assess if you are in a high-risk group:\nOlder adults. As you get older, your immune system may not respond as quickly and as effectively to infectious organisms as it once did.\nInfants and young children. Their immune systems haven\'t fully developed.\nPeople with chronic diseases. Having a chronic condition, such as diabetes or AIDS, or receiving chemotherapy or radiation therapy for cancer, reduces your immune response.\nPregnant people. Pregnancy alters your immune system, making it harder to fight off infections that may affect you and your developing baby.</string>

    <string name="ForeignObjectEar_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Foreign Object in the Ear</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectEar_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If left untreated, a foreign object in the ear can cause pain, infection and hearing loss.\n\nA foreign object in the ear can cause pain, infection and hearing loss. Usually you know if something is stuck in your ear. But small children may not be aware of it. Children may have symptoms such as ear pain, crankiness or crying.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectEar_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Know when to seek help. If there is bleeding, severe pain, drainage or signs of infection, see a health care provider right away. Also, if you know the object is a battery, seek help right away. And if you can\'t easily see the object and you\'ve tried removing it more than once, stop and get care. Delays and many failed tries to remove it can lead to infection and damage.\nNever poke or prod the object. If you use tools such as cotton swabs or matchsticks to pry an object out, they can push it deeper into the ear. This may cause more damage</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectEar_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Usually you know if something is stuck in your ear. But small children may not be aware of it. Children may have symptoms such as ear pain, crankiness or crying.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectEar_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectEar_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Use tweezers. If the object is easy to see and grasp, gently remove it with tweezers.\nUse water. Only wash out the ear canal if you don\'t think there is a hole in the eardrum and no ear tubes are in place. Use a rubber-bulb syringe and warm water to wash the object out of the canal. Don\'t use water to remove batteries, food or plant material.\nUse oil or alcohol for an insect. If the object is an insect, tilt the head so that the ear with the insect is upward. Pour alcohol or warm, but not hot, oil into the ear. The oil can be mineral oil, olive oil or baby oil. The insect should float out. Don\'t use oil if you think there is a hole in the eardrum or if ear tubes are in place.\nNever use liquid if there is a hole in the eardrum or if a child has ear tubes. If you see signs of a hole in the eardrum such as pain, bleeding or discharge, see a health care provider right away.\nRemember, if you can\'t remove the object easily the first time, get help. Also, if the person continues to have pain, discharge from the ear canal, problems hearing or feeling there is something lodged in the ear, see a health care provider.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectEar_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="ForeignObjectEye_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Foreign Object in the Eye</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectEye_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectEye_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Get immediate medical help if:\n\nYou can\'t remove the object with simple irrigation\nThe object is embedded in the eye\nThe person with the object in the eye is experiencing abnormal vision\nPain, redness or the sensation of an object in the eye persists more than 24 hours after the object is removed\nKeep in mind that sometimes an object can scratch your eye. This often feels as though the object is still in the eye even after the object has been removed. This sensation can sometimes take 24 hours to go away.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectEye_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectEye_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectEye_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you get a foreign object in your eye\nWash your hands with soap and water.\nTry to flush the object out of your eye with a gentle stream of clean, warm water. Use an eyecup or a small, clean drinking glass positioned with its rim resting on the bone at the base of your eye socket.\nAnother way to flush a foreign object from your eye is to get into a shower and aim a gentle stream of lukewarm water on your forehead over the affected eye while holding your eyelid open.\nIf you\'re wearing contact lenses, it\'s best to remove the lens before or while you\'re irrigating the surface of the eye with water. Sometimes a foreign body can be stuck to the undersurface of the lens.\nTo help someone else\nWash your hands with soap and water.\nSeat the person in a well-lighted area.\nGently examine the eye to find the object. Pull the lower lid down and ask the person to look up. Then hold the upper lid while the person looks down.\nIf the object is floating in the tear film on the surface of the eye, try using a medicine dropper filled with clean, warm water to flush it out. Or tilt the head back and irrigate the surface of the eye with clean water from a drinking glass or a gentle stream of tap water.\nKeep in mind that sometimes an object can scratch your eye. This often feels as though the object is still in the eye even after the object has been removed. This sensation can sometimes take 24 hours to go away.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectEye_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Don\'t try to remove an object that\'s embedded in the eye.\nDon\'t rub the eye.\nDon\'t try to remove a large object that appears to be embedded in the eye or is sticking out between the lids.</string>

    <string name="ForeignObjectNose_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Foreign Object in the Nose</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectNose_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectNose_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Remove right away if the object is a magnet, battery or expands when wet. These objects can cause severe tissue damage in just hours. If it\'s stuck and you can\'t remove it easily, seek emergency care.\nDon\'t poke or prod the object. Fingers, cotton swabs and other tools might cause swelling and more damage. If the object is pushed deeper into the nose, it may be harder to remove. And it could cause choking.\nDon\'t inhale the object. You might choke. Instead, breathe through your mouth until the object is removed.\nDon\'t wash out the object. You might choke if the object is washed into the airway. Also, some objects may cause more damage when wet.\nBlow out of your nose. The puff of air might free the object. This also is called positive pressure. Don\'t blow hard or constantly. If the object is stuck in only one nostril, gently close the other nostril with your finger. Then, blow out gently but firmly through the affected nostril.\nTry the \"parent\'s kiss.\" If an object is stuck in your child\'s nose, place your mouth over your child\'s mouth to create a seal. Then, give a short, sharp puff of air into your child\'s mouth. The air should push the object out of your child\'s nose. If the object is stuck in one nostril, gently close the other nostril with your finger. Then, blow into your child\'s mouth.\nUse tweezers only if the object is easy to see and grasp. Don\'t try this method if you can\'t easily see or grasp the object. Try blowing air out of the nose first. This might free the object without tweezers.\nSeek help right away if you see symptoms of infection. Or if you can\'t remove the object on the first try.\nCall for emergency medical assistance or go to your local emergency room if these methods fail. Delays and many failed tries to remove a stuck object can lead to infection and damage. Also see a member of your care team if you see symptoms of infection</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectNose_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectNose_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectNose_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectNose_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />


    <string name="ForeignObjectSkin_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Foreign Object in the Skin</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSkin_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectSkin_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek prompt medical help for a foreign object that seems to be more deeply embedded in the skin or muscle</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSkin_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek medical help if:\nThe object is hard to see (as with clear glass) or doesn\'t come out easily (as with a fishhook).\nThe injury involves an eye or is close to an eye.\nThe wound is deep or dirty and the injured person\'s last tetanus vaccination was more than five years ago. The doctor may recommend a booster.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSkin_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Follow these precautions and steps first:\n\nDon\'t try to remove the object. Doing so could cause further harm.\nBandage the wound. First put a piece of gauze over the object. Then, if it helps, put clean padding around the object before binding the wound securely with a bandage or a piece of clean cloth. Take care not to press too hard on the object.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSkin_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">You can usually safely remove a small foreign object — such as a wood splinter, thorn, fiberglass or glass — that\'s just under the surface of the skin:\n\nWash your hands and clean the area well with soap and water.\nUse tweezers cleaned with rubbing alcohol to remove the object. Use a magnifying glass to help you see better.\nIf the object is under the surface of the skin, sterilize a clean, sharp needle by wiping it with rubbing alcohol. Use the needle to gently break the skin over the object and lift up the tip of the object.\nUse a tweezers to grab the end of the object and remove it.\nWash the area again and pat dry. Apply petroleum jelly or an antibiotic ointment.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSkin_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="ForeignObjectInhaled_term">Foreign Object Inhaled</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectInhaled_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you or your child inhales a foreign object, see your health care provider. If an inhaled foreign object causes choking, you\'ll need to perform first aid.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectInhaled_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If a choking person can cough forcefully, let the person keep coughing.\n\nCoughing might naturally remove the stuck object.\n\nIf a person can\'t cough, talk, cry or laugh forcefully, give first aid to the person.\n\nThe American Red Cross recommends the following steps:\n\nGive five back blows. Stand to the side and just behind a choking adult. For a child, kneel down behind. Place your arm across the person\'s chest to support the person\'s body. Bend the person over at the waist to face the ground. Strike five separate times between the person\'s shoulder blades with the heel of your hand.\nGive five abdominal thrusts. If back blows don\'t remove the stuck object, give five abdominal thrusts, also known as the Heimlich maneuver.\nAlternate between five blows and five thrusts until the blockage is dislodged.\nIf you\'re the only rescuer, give back blows and abdominal thrusts first. Then, call 911 or your local emergency number for help. If another person is there, have that person call for help while you give first aid\n\nIf the person who has inhaled an object becomes unconscious:\nLower the person onto the floor, with the back on the floor and arms to the sides.\nClear the airway. If you can see the object, reach a finger into the mouth to sweep out the object. Never finger sweep if you can\'t see the object. You risk pushing the blockage deeper into the airway. This is very risky with young children.\nBegin CPR if the person still doesn\'t respond. If the airway is still blocked, use chest compressions such as those that are used in CPR to remove the stuck object. Only use two rescue breaths per cycle. Recheck the mouth regularly for the object.\nSome sources only teach the abdominal thrust. It\'s OK not to use back blows if you haven\'t learned the back-blow technique. Both approaches are acceptable for adults and children older than age 1.\n\nTo give abdominal thrusts to someone else:\nStand behind the person. For a child, kneel down behind. Place one foot slightly in front of the other for balance. Wrap your arms around the waist. Tip the person forward slightly.\nMake a fist with one hand. Put it just above the person\'s navel.\nGrasp the fist with the other hand. Press into the stomach, also called the abdomen, with a quick, upward thrust — as if trying to lift the person up. For a child, use gentle yet firm pressure to avoid damaging the internal organs.\nGive five abdominal thrusts. Check if the blockage has been removed. Repeat as needed.\nIf the person is pregnant or if you can\'t get your arms around the stomach, give chest thrusts:\nPut your hands at the base of the breastbone, just above the joining of the lowest ribs.\nPress hard into the chest with a quick thrust. This is the same action as the Heimlich maneuver.\nRepeat until the blockage is removed from the airway.\n\nIf you\'re alone and choking:\nCall 911 or your local emergency number right away. Then, give yourself abdominal thrusts, also called the Heimlich maneuver, to remove the item from the airway.\n\nPlace a fist slightly above your navel.\nGrasp your fist with the other hand.\nBend over a hard surface such as a countertop or chair.\nShove your fist inward and upward.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectInhaled_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectInhaled_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectInhaled_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectInhaled_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="ForeignObjectSwallowed_term">Foreign Object Swallowed</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSwallowed_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you swallow a foreign object, it will usually pass through your system without notice. But some objects can get stuck in the tube that connects the mouth and stomach, called the esophagus. Or they can block the airway and cause choking.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSwallowed_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If an object is stuck in your esophagus, you may need to have it removed by your health care provider.\nAlso see your provider right away if the object is:\n\nSharp or pointed. These objects can damage the esophagus.\nA button battery. Batteries can cause severe burns and permanent damage if not removed quickly.\nA magnet. Magnets can pull, press or wear holes through the intestines. It\'s especially risky if you swallow more than one.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSwallowed_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Symptoms include pain from the throat down the middle of the chest and regurgitating food or drink. If you have food stuck in the esophagus, you can try to drink a carbonated beverage to see if that will help it pass.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSwallowed_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ForeignObjectSwallowed_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If an object blocks the airway and causes choking, give first aid.\nIf a choking person can cough forcefully, let the person keep coughing. Coughing might naturally remove the stuck object. If a person can\'t cough, talk, cry or laugh forcefully, give first aid to the person. The American Red Cross recommends the following steps:\n\nGive five back blows. Stand to the side and just behind a choking adult. For a child, kneel down behind. Place your arm across the person\'s chest to support the person\'s body. Bend the person over at the waist to face the ground. Strike five separate times between the person\'s shoulder blades with the heel of your hand.\nGive five abdominal thrusts. If back blows don\'t remove the stuck object, give five abdominal thrusts, also known as the Heimlich maneuver.\nAlternate between five blows and five thrusts until the blockage is dislodged.\nIf you\'re the only rescuer, give back blows and abdominal thrusts first. Then call 911 or your local emergency number for help. If another person is there, have that person call for help while you give first aid.\n\nSome first-aid sources only teach the abdominal thrust. It\'s OK not to use back blows if you haven\'t learned the back-blow technique. Both approaches are acceptable for adults and children older than age 1.\n\nIf the choking person becomes unconscious:\nLower the person onto the floor. Keep the person\'s back on the floor and arms to the sides.\nClear the airway. If you can see the object, reach a finger into the mouth to sweep out the object. Never sweep with your finger if you can\'t see the object because this may push the blockage deeper into the airway. This is an especially high risk with young children.\nBegin CPR if the person still doesn\'t respond. If the airway is still blocked, use chest compressions such as those that are used in CPR to remove the stuck object. If the airway is clear and you give rescue breaths, only use two rescue breaths a cycle. Recheck the mouth regularly for the object.\nTo give abdominal thrusts to someone else:\nStand behind the person. For a child, kneel down behind. Place one foot slightly in front of the other for balance. Wrap your arms around the waist. Tip the person forward slightly.\nMake a fist with one hand. Put it just above the person\'s navel.\nGrasp the fist with the other hand. Press into the stomach, also called the abdomen, with a quick, upward thrust — as if trying to lift the person up. For a child, use gentle yet firm pressure to avoid damaging the internal organs.\nGive five abdominal thrusts. Check to see if the blockage has been removed. Repeat as needed.\nIf the person is pregnant or if you can\'t get your arms around the stomach, give chest thrusts:\nPut your hands on the chest. Place them at the base of the breastbone, just above the joining of the lowest ribs.\nPress hard into the chest with a quick thrust. This is the same action as the Heimlich maneuver.\nRepeat until the blockage is removed from the airway.\n\nIf you\'re alone and choking:\nCall 911 or your local emergency number right away. Then give yourself abdominal thrusts, also called the Heimlich maneuver, to remove the stuck object.\n\nPlace a fist slightly above your navel.\nGrasp your fist with the other hand.\nBend over a hard surface such as a countertop or chair.\nShove your fist inward and upward.\nTo prepare yourself for these situations, learn the Heimlich maneuver and CPR in a certified first-aid training course.</string>
    <string name="ForeignObjectSwallowed_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To prepare yourself for these situations, learn the Heimlich maneuver and CPR in a certified first-aid training course.</string>

    <string name="Fracture_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A fracture is a broken bone. It needs medical care. If the broken bone is the result of major trauma or injury, call 911 or your local emergency number.</string>
    <string name="Fracture_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Fractures (broken bones)</string>
    <string name="Fracture_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call for emergency help if:\n\nThe person with the broken bone doesn\'t respond to you, isn\'t breathing or isn\'t moving. Call 911. Then begin CPR if there\'s no breathing or heartbeat.\nThere\'s heavy bleeding.\nEven gentle pressure or movement causes pain.\nThe limb or joint appears deformed.\nThe bone has broken the skin and is sticking out.\nThe toe of the injured leg or the finger of the injured arm is numb or discolored at the tip.\nYou suspect a bone is broken in the neck, head or back.</string>
    <string name="Fracture_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">The person with the broken bone doesn\'t respond to you, isn\'t breathing or isn\'t moving. Call 911. Then begin CPR if there\'s no breathing or heartbeat.\nThere\'s heavy bleeding.\nEven gentle pressure or movement causes pain.\nThe limb or joint appears deformed.\nThe bone has broken the skin and is sticking out.\nThe toe of the injured leg or the finger of the injured arm is numb or discolored at the tip.\nYou suspect a bone is broken in the neck, head or back.</string>
    <string name="Fracture_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Fracture_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To avoid making the injury worse, don\'t move the person unless you must. Take these actions right away while waiting for medical help:\n\nStop any bleeding. Apply pressure to the wound with a sterile bandage, a clean cloth or a clean piece of clothing.\nKeep the injured area from moving. Don\'t try to realign the bone or push a bone that\'s sticking out back in. If you\'ve been trained in how to splint and medical help isn\'t available right away, apply a splint to the area above and below the fracture sites. Padding the splints can help reduce pain.\nApply ice packs to limit swelling and help relieve pain. Don\'t apply ice directly to the skin. Wrap the ice in a towel, a piece of cloth or some other material.\nTreat for shock. If the person feels faint or is breathing in short, rapid breaths, lay the person down with the head slightly lower than the trunk. If you can, raise the legs.</string>
    <string name="Fracture_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="Frostbite_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Frostbite is when skin and underlying tissues freeze after being exposed to very cold temperatures. It causes a cold feeling followed by numbness. As the frostbite gets worse, the affected skin may change color and become hard or waxy-looking.\n\nThe areas most likely to be affected are the fingers, toes, ears, cheeks, chin and tip of the nose.</string>
    <string name="Frostbite_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Frostbite</string>
    <string name="Frostbite_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek emergency care for:\n\nIntense pain even after taking a pain reliever and rewarming.\nIntense shivering.\nSlurred speech.\nDrowsiness.\nTrouble walking.\nSuspected hypothermia. Symptoms of hypothermia are intense shivering, drowsiness, confusion, fumbling hands and slurred speech.</string>
    <string name="Frostbite_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">You can treat mild frostbite (frostnip) yourself. All other frostbite requires medical attention. First-aid steps for frostbite are as follows:\n\nProtect your skin from further damage. If there\'s any chance the affected areas will freeze again, don\'t thaw them. If they\'re already thawed, wrap them up so that they don\'t refreeze.\n\nIf you\'re outside, warm frostbitten hands by tucking them into your armpits. Protect your face, nose or ears by covering the area with dry, gloved hands.\n\nGet out of the cold, remove wet clothes and wrap up in a warm blanket.\nGently rewarm frostbitten areas. If possible, soak the skin with frostbite in a tub or sink of warm water for about 30 minutes. For frostbite on the nose or ears, cover the area with warm, wet cloths for about 30 minutes.\nDrink a warm, nonalcoholic beverage.\nTake a nonprescription pain reliever if needed.\nRemove rings or other tight items. Do this before the injured area swells with rewarming.</string>
    <string name="Frostbite_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Don\'t rub the affected skin with snow or anything else.\nDon\'t walk on frostbitten feet or toes if possible.\nDon\'t rewarm frostbitten skin with direct heat, such as a stove, heat lamp, fireplace or heating pad. This can cause burns.\nDon’t drink alcohol.\nDon\'t apply direct heat. For example, don\'t warm the skin with a heating pad, a heat lamp, a blow-dryer or a car heater.</string>
    <string name="Frostbite_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek emergency care for:\n\nIntense pain even after taking a pain reliever and rewarming.\nIntense shivering.\nSlurred speech.\nDrowsiness.\nTrouble walking.\nSuspected hypothermia. Symptoms of hypothermia are intense shivering, drowsiness, confusion, fumbling hands and slurred speech.</string>
    <string name="Frostbite_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">The areas most likely to be affected are the fingers, toes, ears, cheeks, chin and tip of the nose.</string>

    <string name="Gastroenteritis_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Gastroenteritis</string>
    <string name="Gastroenteritis_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Gastroenteritis is an inflammation of the stomach and intestines that can cause symptoms that are not pleasant, including watery diarrhea, nausea and vomiting. Gastroenteritis is often called the \"stomach flu.\"</string>
    <string name="Gastroenteritis_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Common symptoms include:\nCommon symptoms include:Nausea and vomiting.\nDiarrhea.\nAbdominal cramps.\nLow-grade fever (sometimes).\nSeek medical attention if:\nVomiting lasts more than two days.\nDiarrhea lasts more than several days.\nDiarrhea turns bloody.\nFever is more than 102 Fahrenheit (39 degrees Celsius) or higher.\nYou get lightheaded or faint when you stand.\nConfusion develops.\nStomach pain develops.\n\nSeek medical attention if your child:\nBecomes unusually drowsy.\nVomits frequently or vomits blood.\nHas bloody diarrhea.\nShows signs of dehydration, such as dry mouth and skin, marked thirst, sunken eyes, or crying without tears. In an infant, be alert to the soft spot on the top of the head becoming sunken and to diapers that remain dry for more than three hours.\nIs an infant and has a fever.\nIs older than 3 months of age and has a fever of 102 Fahrenheit (39 degrees Celsius) or more.</string>
    <string name="Gastroenteritis_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Gastroenteritis_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Gastroenteritis_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you suspect you have gastroenteritis:\nSip liquids. Sip a sports drink or water to prevent dehydration. Drinking fluids too quickly can make nausea and vomiting worse. Take small sips often over a couple of hours, instead of drinking a large amount at once.\nTake note of urination. You should be urinating at regular intervals, and your urine should be light and clear. Infrequent passage of dark urine is a sign of dehydration. Dizziness and lightheadedness also are symptoms of dehydration. If any of these symptoms occur and you can\'t drink enough fluids, seek medical attention.\nEase back into eating. Try to eat small amounts of food frequently if you experience nausea. Otherwise, slowly begin to eat bland, easy-to-digest foods, such as soda crackers, toast, gelatin, bananas, applesauce, rice and chicken. Stop eating if your nausea returns. Avoid milk and dairy products, caffeine, alcohol, nicotine, and fatty or highly seasoned foods for a few days.\nGet plenty of rest. The illness and dehydration can make you weak and tired.\n\nIf you suspect gastroenteritis in your child:\nEncourage your child to rest.\nWhen your child\'s vomiting stops, begin to offer small amounts of an oral rehydration solution (Ceralyte, Enfalyte, Pedialyte). Don\'t use only water or only apple juice. Drinking fluids too quickly can worsen the nausea and vomiting, so try to give small frequent sips over a couple of hours, instead of drinking a large amount at once. Try using a water dropper of rehydration solution instead of a bottle or cup.\nGradually introduce bland, easy-to-digest foods, such as toast, rice, bananas and potatoes. Avoid giving your child full-fat dairy products, such as whole milk and ice cream, and sugary foods, such as sodas and candy. These can make diarrhea worse.\nIf you\'re breastfeeding, let your baby nurse. If your baby is bottle-fed, offer a small amount of an oral rehydration solution or regular formula.</string>
    <string name="Gastroenteritis_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="HeadTrauma_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Head Trauma</string>
    <string name="HeadTrauma_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="HeadTrauma_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To give first aid to a person who has head trauma, call 911 or your local emergency number. Any of the following symptoms may indicate a serious head injury:\n\nAdults\nSevere head or facial bleeding.\nBleeding or fluid leakage from the nose or ears.\nVomiting.\nSevere headache.\nChange in consciousness for more than a few seconds.\nBlack-and-blue discoloration below the eyes or behind the ears.\nNot breathing.\nConfusion.\nAgitation.\nLoss of balance.\nWeakness or an inability to use an arm or leg.\nUnequal pupil size.\nSlurred speech.\nSeizures.\nChildren\nAny of the symptoms for adults.\nPersistent crying.\nRefusal to eat.\nBulging in the soft spot on the front of the head of infants.\nRepeated vomiting.</string>
    <string name="HeadTrauma_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Administer the following first-aid steps while waiting for emergency medical help to arrive:\nKeep the person still. The injured person should lie down with the head and shoulders slightly elevated. Don\'t move the person unless necessary. Avoid moving the person\'s neck. If the person is wearing a helmet, don\'t remove it.\nStop any bleeding. Apply firm pressure to the wound with sterile gauze or a clean cloth. But don\'t apply direct pressure to the wound if you suspect a skull fracture.\nWatch for changes in breathing and alertness. If the person shows no signs of circulation — no breathing, coughing or movement — begin CPR.</string>
    <string name="HeadTrauma_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="HeadTrauma_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Head trauma that results in concussion symptoms need to be evaluated by a medical professional. Concussion symptoms include nausea, unsteadiness, headaches or difficulty concentrating.</string>
    <string name="HeadTrauma_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="Headache_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Headache</string>
    <string name="Headache_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Most headaches are minor, and you can treat them with a pain reliever. Some headaches, however, signal a dangerous or serious medical problem. Don\'t ignore headaches that aren\'t explained or headaches that steadily worsen.</string>
    <string name="Headache_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Headache_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Get immediate medical attention if your headache:\n\nDevelops suddenly and severely.\nPersists for several days.\nCauses mental confusion or loss of consciousness.\nHappens with seizures.\nImmediate medical attention also is needed if your headache occurs with new:\n\nDizziness or loss of balance.\nWeakness or paralysis, such as in the arms or legs.\nNumbness.\nDifficulty speaking or understanding speech.\nReddened eye.\nAlso seek medical attention if your headache:\n\nOccurs with a fever, stiff neck or rash.\nIs accompanied by changes in vision, such as blurring or seeing halos around lights.\nIs serious and follows a recent sore throat or respiratory infection.\nBegins or worsens after a head injury, fall or bump.\nIs triggered by changing the position of your head, coughing, sneezing, bending or physical activity.\nIs a different type of headache from your usual type and you\'re older than 50.</string>
    <string name="Headache_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Headache_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Headache_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="HeartAttack_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heart Attack</string>
    <string name="HeartAttack_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A heart attack usually causes chest pain for more than 15 minutes. The chest pain may be mild or severe. Some people don\'t have any chest pain or pressure. Women tend to have more-vague symptoms, such as nausea or a brief or sharp pain felt in the neck, arm or back.\n\nSome heart attacks strike suddenly. But many people have warning signs hours or days in advance.</string>
    <string name="HeartAttack_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call 911 or your local emergency number. Don\'t ignore the symptoms of a heart attack. If you can\'t get an ambulance or emergency vehicle to come to you, have someone drive you to the nearest hospital. Drive yourself only if you have no other option.\nTake aspirin, if recommended. Aspirin helps prevent blood clotting. Taking aspirin during a heart attack may reduce heart damage. Don\'t take an aspirin unless a healthcare professional says to do so. Don\'t delay calling 911 to take an aspirin. Call for emergency help first.\nTake nitroglycerin, if prescribed. If you think you\'re having a heart attack and have a prescription for this medicine, take it as directed while waiting for emergency medical help.\nStart CPR if the person doesn\'t have a pulse or isn\'t breathing. If you\'re untrained in CPR, do hands-only CPR. That means push hard and fast on the person\'s chest. Do this about 100 to 120 times a minute. If you\'re trained in CPR and confident in your ability, start with 30 chest compressions before giving two rescue breaths.\nUse an automated external defibrillator (AED) if one is immediately available and the person is unconscious. The device delivers shocks to reset the heart rhythm. AEDs come with step-by-step voice instructions for their use. They\'re programmed to allow a shock only when appropriate.</string>
    <string name="HeartAttack_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Chest pain that may feel like pressure, tightness, pain, squeezing or aching.\nPain or discomfort that spreads to the shoulder, arm, back, neck, jaw, teeth or sometimes the upper belly.\nCold sweats.\nFatigue.\nHeartburn or indigestion.\nLightheadedness or sudden dizziness.\nNausea.\nShortness of breath.</string>
    <string name="HeartAttack_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="HeartAttack_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Start CPR if the person doesn\'t have a pulse or isn\'t breathing. If you\'re untrained in CPR, do hands-only CPR. That means push hard and fast on the person\'s chest. Do this about 100 to 120 times a minute. If you\'re trained in CPR and confident in your ability, start with 30 chest compressions before giving two rescue breaths.\nUse an automated external defibrillator (AED) if one is immediately available and the person is unconscious. The device delivers shocks to reset the heart rhythm. AEDs come with step-by-step voice instructions for their use. They\'re programmed to allow a shock only when appropriate.</string>
    <string name="HeartAttack_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Take aspirin, if recommended. Aspirin helps prevent blood clotting. Taking aspirin during a heart attack may reduce heart damage. Don\'t take an aspirin unless a healthcare professional says to do so. Don\'t delay calling 911 to take an aspirin. Call for emergency help first.\nTake nitroglycerin, if prescribed. If you think you\'re having a heart attack and have a prescription for this medicine, take it as directed while waiting for emergency medical help.</string>

    <string name="HeatCramps_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heat Cramps</string>
    <string name="HeatCramps_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heat cramps are painful muscle spasms that can happen during activity in hot environments. People who sweat a lot may be prone to heat cramps. That\'s because the fluid and electrolyte loss that occurs through sweating often contributes to heat cramps.</string>
    <string name="HeatCramps_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heat cramps most often affect the muscles of the calves, arms, abdomen and back. But heat cramps may happen to any muscle group involved in exercise.</string>
    <string name="HeatCramps_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Rest briefly and cool down.\nDrink clear juice, such as apple juice, or a sports drink that has electrolytes.\nDo gentle, range-of-motion stretching and gentle massage of the affected muscle group.\nDon\'t do any strenuous activity for a few hours after heat cramps go away.</string>
    <string name="HeatCramps_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">"Heat cramps are painful muscle spasms that can happen during activity in hot environments. People who sweat a lot may be prone to heat cramps. "</string>
    <string name="HeatCramps_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="HeatCramps_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call your healthcare professional if your heat cramps don\'t go away within one hour. You should also seek medical attention if you have heart problems or are on a low-sodium diet.</string>

    <string name="InsectBites_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Insect Bites and Bee Stings</string>


    <string name="Sunburn_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Sunburn</string>


    <string name="ToothLoss_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Tooth Loss</string>


    <string name="Heatstroke_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heatstroke</string>
    <string name="Heatstroke_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heatstroke happens when body temperature rises quickly and a person can\'t cool down. It can be life-threatening by causing damage to the brain and other vital organs. It may be caused by doing strenuous activity in the heat or by being in a hot place for too long.\n\nHeatstroke can happen without having any previous heat-related condition, such as heat exhaustion.</string>
    <string name="Heatstroke_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Fever of 104 degrees Fahrenheit (40 degrees Celsius) or greater.\nChanges in mental status or behavior, such as confusion, agitation and slurred speech.\nHot, dry skin or heavy sweating.\nNausea and vomiting.\nFlushed skin.\nRapid pulse.\nRapid breathing.\nHeadache.\nFainting.\nSeizure.\nComa.</string>
    <string name="Heatstroke_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you suspect heatstroke, call 911 or your local emergency number. Then move the person out of the heat right away. Cool the person through whatever means available. For example:\n\nPut the person in a cool tub of water or a cool shower.\nSpray the person with a garden hose.\nSponge the person with cool water.\nFan the person while misting with cool water.\nPlace ice packs or cool, wet towels on the neck, armpits and groin.\nCover the person with cool, damp sheets.</string>
    <string name="Heatstroke_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If the person is conscious, offer chilled water, a sports drink containing electrolytes or another nonalcoholic beverage without caffeine.\n\nBegin CPR if the person loses consciousness and shows no signs of circulation, such as breathing, coughing or movement.</string>
    <string name="Heatstroke_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heatstroke can happen without having any previous heat-related condition, such as heat exhaustion</string>
    <string name="Heatstroke_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="HumanBites_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Human Bites</string>
    <string name="HumanBites_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Human bites can be as dangerous as or even more dangerous than animal bites because of the types of bacteria and viruses in the human mouth. A human bite could be accidental or on purpose, with most bites due to another person. A human bite could arise when you cut your knuckles on another person\'s teeth, as might happen in a fight. Or it could be due to a cut on your knuckles from your teeth, such as from a fall. Human bites that break the skin can become infected.</string>
    <string name="HumanBites_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Stop the bleeding by applying pressure with a clean, dry cloth.\nWash the wound thoroughly with soap and water.\nApply a clean bandage. Cover the affected area with a nonstick bandage.\nSeek emergency medical care.</string>
    <string name="HumanBites_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="HumanBites_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="HumanBites_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="HumanBites_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you haven\'t had a tetanus shot within five years, your healthcare professional may recommend a booster. In this case, get the booster shot within 48 hours of the injury.</string>

    <string name="Hypothermia_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Hypothermia</string>
    <string name="Hypothermia_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Hypothermia happens when the body loses heat faster than it can produce heat and the body temperature falls below 95 degrees Fahrenheit (35 degrees Celsius). Left untreated, it can be life-threatening.</string>
    <string name="Hypothermia_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Hypothermia is often caused by exposure to cold weather or immersion in cold water. Ongoing exposure to cool indoor temperatures also can cause hypothermia, especially in older adults and babies. Being exhausted or dehydrated increases the risk of hypothermia.</string>
    <string name="Hypothermia_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you suspect someone has hypothermia, call 911 or your local emergency number.</string>
    <string name="Hypothermia_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Shivering, though this may stop as body temperature drops.\nSlurred speech or mumbling.\nSlow, shallow breathing.\nWeak pulse.\nClumsiness or lack of coordination.\nDrowsiness or very low energy.\nConfusion or memory loss.\nLoss of consciousness.\nIn infants, bright red, cold skin.</string>
    <string name="Hypothermia_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To help someone with hypothermia, take these steps immediately:\n\nGently move the person out of the cold. If going indoors isn\'t possible, protect the person from the wind, especially around the neck and head. Insulate the individual from the cold ground, such as by laying a blanket underneath the person.\nGently remove wet clothing. Replace wet things with warm, dry coats or blankets.\nIf further warming is needed, do so gradually and focus on the center of the body. For example, apply warm, dry compresses to the neck, chest and groin. The CDC says that another option is using an electric blanket, if available. If a hot water bottle or chemical hot pack is used, first wrap it in a towel before applying.\nOffer the person warm, sweet, nonalcoholic drinks.\nBegin CPR if the person shows no signs of life, such as breathing, coughing or movement.</string>
    <string name="Hypothermia_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Do not rewarm the person too quickly, such as with a heating lamp or hot bath.\nDon\'t attempt to warm the arms and legs. Heating or massaging the limbs can stress the heart and lungs.\nDon\'t give the person alcohol or cigarettes. Alcohol hinders the rewarming process, and tobacco products interfere with circulation that is needed for rewarming.</string>

    <string name="InsectBites_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Most insect bites and stings are mild and can be treated at home. They might cause itching, swelling and stinging that go away in a day or two. Some bites or stings can transmit disease-causing bacteria, viruses or parasites. Stings from bees, yellow jackets, wasps, hornets and fire ants might cause a severe allergic reaction (anaphylaxis).</string>
    <string name="InsectBites_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Ask whether the injured person is carrying an epinephrine autoinjector (Auvi-Q, others). Ask whether you should help inject the medicine. This is usually done by pressing the autoinjector against the thigh and holding it in place for several seconds.\nLoosen tight clothing and cover the person with a blanket.\nDon\'t offer anything to drink.\nIf needed, position the person to prevent choking on vomit</string>
    <string name="InsectBites_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call 911 or your local medical emergency number if a child is stung by a scorpion or if anyone is having a serious reaction that suggests anaphylaxis, even if it\'s just one or two of the following symptoms:\nTrouble breathing.\nSwelling of the lips, face, eyelids or throat.\nDizziness, fainting or unconsciousness.\nA weak and rapid pulse.\nHives.\nNausea, vomiting or diarrhea.</string>
    <string name="InsectBites_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="InsectBitesInsectBites_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="StringFormatInvalid,UnusedResources">To treat a mild reaction to an insect bite or sting:\n\nMove to a safe area to avoid more bites or stings.\nRemove any stingers.\nGently wash the area with soap and water.\nApply to the affected skin a cloth dampened with cold water or filled with ice. Keep it on for 10 to 20 minutes. This helps reduce pain and swelling.\nIf the injury is on an arm or leg, raise it.\nApply to the affected skin calamine lotion, baking soda paste, or 0.5% or 1% hydrocortisone cream. Do this several times a day until your symptoms go away.\nTake an anti-itch medicine by mouth to reduce itching. Options include nonprescription cetirizine, fexofenadine (Allegra Allergy, Children\'s Allegra Allergy), loratadine (Claritin). These types of medicines are also called antihistamines.\nTake a nonprescription pain reliever as needed.</string>
    <string name="InsectBites_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">See a healthcare professional if the swelling gets worse, the site shows signs of infection or you don\'t feel well.</string>

    <string name="MotionSickness_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Any type of transportation can cause motion sickness. It can strike suddenly, progressing from a feeling of uneasiness to a cold sweat, dizziness and vomiting. It usually quiets down as soon as the motion stops. The more you travel, the more easily you\'ll adjust to being in motion.</string>
    <string name="MotionSickness_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Motion Sickness</string>
    <string name="MotionSickness_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">You might avoid motion sickness by planning ahead. When traveling, avoid sitting in the rear of the vehicle or in seats that face backward. Pick seats where you\'ll feel motion least:\n\nBy ship, request a cabin in the front or middle of the ship near the water level.\nBy plane, ask for a seat over the front edge of a wing. Once aboard, direct the air vent flow to your face.\nBy train, take a forward-facing seat near the front and next to a window.\nBy automobile, drive or sit in the front passenger\'s seat. Children should be in age-appropriate seats and restraints.</string>
    <string name="MotionSickness_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Focus on the horizon or on a distant, stationary object. Don\'t read or use electronic devices while traveling.\nKeep your head still, while resting against a seat back.\nDon\'t smoke and don\'t sit near smokers.\nAvoid strong odors, spicy and greasy foods, and alcohol.\nTake an antihistamine, which you can buy without a prescription. Medicines include dimenhydrinate (Dramamine, Driminate, others) and meclizine (Dramamine Less Drowsy, Travel-Ease, others). Dimenhydrinate is safe for children older than age 2. Take these medicines at least 30 to 60 minutes before you travel. Expect drowsiness as a side effect.\nConsider scopolamine, available in a prescription adhesive patch called Transderm Scop. Several hours before you plan to travel, apply the patch behind your ear for 72-hour protection. Talk to your health care provider before using the medicine if you have health problems such as glaucoma or urine retention.\nTry ginger. A ginger supplement combined with ginger snaps, ginger ale or candied ginger might help curb nausea.\nEat lightly. Some people find that nibbling on plain crackers and sipping cold water or a carbonated drink without caffeine help.</string>
    <string name="MotionSickness_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="MotionSickness_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="MotionSickness_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="Nosebleeds_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Nosebleeds</string>
    <string name="Nosebleeds_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Nosebleeds, also called epistaxis (ep-ih-STAK-sis), are common. They happen when the tender blood vessels in the nose break. Common nosebleed causes can include changes of season, dryness, scratching, some medicines and injuries. People on blood thinners may have worse nosebleeds than do others. Most often nosebleeds are only annoying and not a true medical problem. But they can be both.</string>
    <string name="Nosebleeds_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Nosebleeds_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Think about using a humidifier. Adding more moisture in your home may help relieve nasal bleeding.</string>
    <string name="Nosebleeds_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek emergency care if:\n\nNosebleeds involve a greater than expected amount of blood.\nNosebleeds last longer than 30 minutes.\nYou feel faint or lightheaded.\nThe nosebleed follows a fall or an accident. Bleeding after a fall or an injury to the head or face could mean that you have broken the nose.</string>
    <string name="Nosebleeds_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Self-care for a common nosebleed\nSit up and lean forward. Keep the head up. Lean forward so the blood doesn\'t go down the throat. This could cause you to choke or have an upset stomach.\nGently blow your nose. This will clear any blood clots.\nPinch the nose. Use the thumb and a finger to pinch both nostrils shut. Breathe through the mouth. Keep pinching for 10 to 15 minutes. Pinching puts pressure on the blood vessels and helps stop the blood flow.\n\nIf the bleeding doesn\'t stop, pinch the nose again for up to 15 minutes. Don\'t let go for at least five minutes even to check if the bleeding has stopped. Seek emergency care if the bleeding doesn\'t stop after the second try.\n\nPrevent another nosebleed. Don\'t pick or blow the nose. And don\'t drop the head below the heart or lift anything heavy for many hours. Gently put a saline gel (Ayr), antibiotic ointment (Neosporin) or petroleum jelly (Vaseline) on the inside of the nose. Put most of the salve on the middle part of the nose, also called the septum. Steam, humidifiers or an ice pack across the bridge of the nose also may help.\nIf you have another nosebleed, try first-aid steps again. This time, spray both sides of the nose with a nasal spray that has oxymetazoline in it (Afrin). Do this after blowing the nose. Then pinch the nose again. Seek medical help if the bleeding does not stop.\nWhen to contact your doctor\nCall a member of your care team if:\n\nYou have nosebleeds often. You may need to have a blood vessel cauterized. Cautery is a method that burns and seals blood vessels using electric current, silver nitrate or a laser. Also, a care provider might pack the nose with special gauze or an inflatable latex balloon. Both packing methods put pressure on the blood vessel and stop the bleeding.\nYou have nosebleeds and you\'re taking blood thinners. If you\'re taking medicines such as aspirin or warfarin (Jantoven), your care team may change the medicine dose.</string>
    <string name="Nosebleeds_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">The nosebleed follows a fall or an accident. Bleeding after a fall or an injury to the head or face could mean that you have broken the nose.</string>

    <string name="HeatExhaustion_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heat Exhaustion</string>
    <string name="HeatExhaustion_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heat exhaustion is one of the heat-related syndromes. These syndromes vary in seriousness, ranging from mild to possibly life-threatening. Other types of heat-related illnesses include heat rash, heat cramps, heat syncope and heatstroke.\n\nHeat exhaustion can happen when the body loses too much water or salt — usually because of heavy sweating or dehydration. It can begin suddenly or happen over time, usually after working, exercising or playing in the heat.</string>
    <string name="HeatExhaustion_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Cool, moist skin with goose bumps when in the heat.\nHeavy sweating.\nFaintness.\nDizziness.\nFatigue.\nWeak, rapid pulse.\nLow blood pressure after standing up.\nMuscle cramps.\nNausea or vomiting.\nHeadache.\nExtreme thirst.\nMild confusion.\nDecreased urine output.</string>
    <string name="HeatExhaustion_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call 911 or your local emergency number if the affected person:\n\nFaints.\nBecomes agitated.\nIs confused.\nHas a seizure.\nIs not able to drink.\nHas a core body temperature – measured with a rectal thermometer – of 104 degrees Fahrenheit (40 degrees Celsius), which indicates heatstroke.</string>
    <string name="HeatExhaustion_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Move the person out of the heat and into a shady or air-conditioned place.\nLay the person down and raise the legs and feet slightly.\nRemove tight or heavy clothing.\nHave the person sip chilled water, a sports drink containing electrolytes or another nonalcoholic beverage without caffeine.\nCool the person by spraying or sponging with cool water and fanning.\nMonitor the person carefully.</string>
    <string name="HeatExhaustion_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Heat exhaustion can happen when the body loses too much water or salt — usually because of heavy sweating or dehydration. It can begin suddenly or happen over time, usually after working, exercising or playing in the heat.</string>
    <string name="HeatExhaustion_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Contact a healthcare professional if symptoms get worse or if the person doesn\'t improve after taking first-aid measures.</string>

    <string name="Poisoning_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Poisoning is injury or death due to swallowing, inhaling, touching or injecting various drugs, chemicals, venoms or gases. Many substances — such as drugs and carbon monoxide — are poisonous only in higher concentrations or dosages. Certain types of cleaners are only harmful if ingested, while others also emit toxic gases/fumes. Children are particularly sensitive to even small amounts of certain drugs and chemicals.</string>
    <string name="Poisoning_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Poisoning</string>
    <string name="Poisoning_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Swallowed poison. Remove anything remaining in the person\'s mouth. If the suspected poison is a household cleaner or other chemical, read the container\'s label and follow instructions for accidental poisoning.\nPoison on the skin. Remove any contaminated clothing using gloves. Rinse the skin for 15 to 20 minutes in a shower or with a hose.\nPoison in the eye. Gently flush the eye with cool or lukewarm water for 20 minutes or until help arrives.\nInhaled poison. Get the person into fresh air as soon as possible.\nIf the person vomits, turn his or her head to the side to prevent choking.\nBegin CPR if the person shows no signs of life, such as moving, breathing or coughing.\nCall Poison Help at 800–222–1222 in the United States or your regional poison control for additional instructions.\nHave somebody gather pill bottles, packages or containers with labels, and any other information about the poison to send along with the ambulance team.</string>
    <string name="Poisoning_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Poisoning signs and symptoms can mimic other conditions, such as seizure, alcohol intoxication, stroke and insulin reaction. Signs and symptoms of poisoning may include:\n\nBurns or redness around the mouth and lips\nBreath that smells like chemicals, such as gasoline or paint thinner\nVomiting\nDifficulty breathing\nDrowsiness\nConfusion or other altered mental status\nIf you suspect poisoning, be alert for clues such as empty pill bottles or packages, scattered pills, and burns, stains and odors on the person or nearby objects. With a child, consider the possibility that he or she may have applied medicated patches, taken prescription medications or swallowed a button battery.</string>
    <string name="Poisoning_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">How you treat someone who may have been poisoned depends on:\n\nThe person\'s symptoms\nThe person\'s age\nWhether you know the type and amount of the substance that caused poisoning</string>
    <string name="Poisoning_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If the person is at risk of overdose of opioid pain medication and naloxone (Narcan) is available, please administer. Increasingly, health care providers are giving people Narcan injectable prescriptions if they are at risk of overdose. Loved ones should be familiar with how to use them.\n\nCaution\nSyrup of ipecac. Don\'t give syrup of ipecac or do anything to induce vomiting. Expert groups, including the American Association of Poison Control Centers and the American Academy of Pediatrics, no longer endorse using ipecac in children or adults who have taken pills or other potentially poisonous substances. No good evidence proves its effectiveness, and it often can do more harm than good.\n\nIf you still have old bottles of syrup of ipecac in your home, throw them away.\n\nButton batteries. The small, flat batteries used in watches and other electronics — particularly the larger, nickel-sized ones — are especially dangerous to small children. A battery stuck in the esophagus can cause severe tissue burns.\n\nIf you suspect that a child has swallowed one of these batteries, immediately take him or her for an emergency X-ray to determine its location. If the battery is in the esophagus, it will have to be removed. If it has passed into the stomach, it\'s usually safe to allow it to pass on through the intestinal tract.\n\nMedicated patches. If you think a child got hold of medicated patches — adhesive products for transdermal drug delivery — carefully inspect the child\'s skin and remove any that are attached. Also check the roof of the mouth, where medicated patches can get stuck if the child sucks on them.</string>
    <string name="Poisoning_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call Poison Help at 800–222–1222 in the United States or your regional poison control center in the following situations:\n\nThe person is stable and has no symptoms\nThe person is going to be transported to the local emergency department\nBe ready to describe the person\'s symptoms, age, weight, other medications he or she is taking, and any information you have about the poison. Try to determine the amount ingested and how long since the person was exposed to it. If possible, have on hand the pill bottle, medication package or other suspect container so that you can refer to its label when speaking with the poison control center.</string>

    <string name="PunctureWounds_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Puncture Wounds</string>
    <string name="PunctureWounds_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A puncture wound, such as from stepping on a nail, doesn\'t usually cause much bleeding. But these wounds are often deep and can be dangerous because of the risk of infection.</string>
    <string name="PunctureWounds_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Get medical help at once if your wound:\n\nKeeps bleeding after a few minutes of direct pressure.\nIs due to an animal or human bite.\nIs deep and dirty.\nIs caused by a metal object.\nIs deep and to the head, neck, scrotum, chest or abdomen.\nIs over a joint and could be deep.\nIs due to an assault or attempted suicide.</string>
    <string name="PunctureWounds_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek medical care if your wound shows signs of infection, such as:\n\nFever.\nRedness, swelling, warmth or increasing pain around the wound.\nBad smell coming from the wound.\nPus coming out of the wound.\nRed streaks around the wound or going up your arm or leg.</string>
    <string name="PunctureWounds_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="PunctureWounds_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Wash your hands. This helps prevent infection.\nStop the bleeding. Apply gentle pressure with a clean bandage or cloth.\nClean the wound. Rinse the wound with clear water for 5 to 10 minutes. If dirt or debris remains in the wound, use a washcloth to gently scrub it off. See your health care team if you can\'t remove all of the dirt or debris.\nApply an ointment. Apply a thin layer of an antibiotic cream or ointment (Neosporin, Polysporin). For the first two days, rewash the area and reapply the antibiotic when you change the dressing. Certain ingredients in some ointments can cause a mild rash in some people. If a rash appears, stop using the product and seek medical care. For those people who could have an allergic reaction to antibiotic cream or ointment, petroleum jelly (Vaseline) may be used.\nCover the wound. Bandages help keep the wound clean.\nChange the dressing. Do this daily or whenever the bandage becomes wet or dirty.\nWatch for signs of infection. See a doctor if the wound isn\'t healing or you notice any increasing pain, pus, swelling or fever. Spreading redness is a sign of infection. You may not be able to see redness on brown or Black skin, or the infection\'s streaks may look purplish-gray or darker than your usual skin color.</string>
    <string name="PunctureWounds_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you haven\'t had a tetanus shot in the past five years and the wound is deep or dirty, your health care professional may recommend a booster. You should have a booster shot within 48 hours of your injury.\n\nIf the wound was caused by a cat or a dog, try to confirm that its rabies vaccination is up to date. If it was caused by a wild animal, seek advice from your doctor about which animals are most likely to carry rabies.</string>

    <string name="SevereBleeding_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Severe Bleeding</string>
    <string name="SevereBleeding_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="SevereBleeding_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call 911 or your local emergency number if the wound is deep or you\'re not sure how serious it is. Don\'t move the injured person except if needed to avoid further injury.\n\nBefore checking for the source of the wound, put on disposable gloves and other personal protective equipment if you have them.\n\nRemove any clothing or debris from the wound. Look for the source of the bleeding. There could be more than one injury. Remove any obvious debris but don\'t try to clean the wound. Don\'t remove large or deeply embedded objects, and don\'t probe the wound.\nStop the bleeding. Cover the wound with sterile gauze or a clean cloth. Press on it firmly with the palm of your hand until bleeding stops. But don\'t press on an eye injury or embedded object. Don\'t press on a head wound if you suspect a skull fracture.\n\nWrap the wound with a thick bandage or clean cloth and tape. Lift the wound above heart level if possible.\n\nHelp the injured person lie down. If possible, place the person on a rug or blanket to prevent loss of body heat. Elevate the feet if you notice signs of shock, such as weakness, clammy skin or a rapid pulse. Calmly reassure the injured person.\nAdd more bandages as needed. If the blood seeps through the bandage, add more gauze or cloth on top of the existing bandage. Then keep pressing firmly on the area.\nTourniquets: A tourniquet is effective in controlling life-threatening bleeding from a limb. If needed, apply a commercially made tourniquet if it\'s available and you\'re trained in how to use it. Don\'t use an improvised tourniquet, such as a scarf or a belt.\n\nWhen emergency help arrives, tell them how long the tourniquet has been in place.\n\nKeep the person still. If you\'re waiting for emergency help to arrive, try to keep the injured person from moving.\n\nIf you haven\'t called for emergency help, get the injured person to an emergency room as soon as possible.\n\nWash your hands. After helping the injured person, wash your hands, even if it doesn\'t look like any blood got on your hands.</string>
    <string name="SevereBleeding_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="SevereBleeding_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="SevereBleeding_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="SevereBleeding_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="Shock_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Shock is a critical condition brought on by the sudden drop in blood flow through the body. Shock may result from trauma, heatstroke, blood loss or an allergic reaction. It also may result from severe infection, poisoning, severe burns or other causes.\n\nShock keeps organs from getting enough blood or oxygen. If shock is not treated, it can lead to permanent organ damage or even death.</string>
    <string name="Shock_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Shock</string>
    <string name="Shock_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">After calling 911 or your local emergency number, take the following steps right away:\n\nLay the person down and elevate the legs and feet slightly, unless you think this may cause pain or further injury.\nKeep the person still.\nBegin CPR if the person shows no signs of life, such as not breathing, coughing or moving.\nLoosen tight clothing and, if needed, cover the person with a blanket to prevent chilling.\nIf the person vomits or is bleeding from the mouth, and no spinal injury is suspected, turn the person onto a side to prevent choking.</string>
    <string name="Shock_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Cool, clammy skin.\nPale or ashen skin.\nA gray or bluish tinge to lips or fingernails.\nRapid pulse.\nRapid breathing.\nNausea or vomiting.\nEnlarged pupils.\nWeakness or fatigue.\nDizziness or fainting.\nChanges in mental status or behavior, such as anxiousness or agitation.</string>
    <string name="Shock_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Shock may result from trauma, heatstroke, blood loss or an allergic reaction. It also may result from severe infection, poisoning, severe burns or other causes.</string>
    <string name="Shock_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Lay the person down and elevate the legs and feet slightly, unless you think this may cause pain or further injury.\nKeep the person still.\nBegin CPR if the person shows no signs of life, such as not breathing, coughing or moving.\nLoosen tight clothing and, if needed, cover the person with a blanket to prevent chilling.\nIf the person vomits or is bleeding from the mouth, and no spinal injury is suspected, turn the person onto a side to prevent choking.</string>
    <string name="Shock_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Don\'t let the person eat or drink anything.\nDon\'t move the person unless it\'s needed.</string>

    <string name="Snakebites_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Most snakes aren\'t dangerous to people. Only about 15% of snakes worldwide and 20% in the United States can inject poison when they bite. These snakes are called venomous. In North America, these include the rattlesnake, coral snake, water moccasin, also called cottonmouth, and copperhead. Their bites can cause serious injuries and sometimes death.</string>
    <string name="Snakebites_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Snakebites</string>
    <string name="Snakebites_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If a venomous snake bites you, call 911 or your local emergency number right away, especially if the bitten area changes color, swells or is painful. Many emergency rooms have antivenom drugs, which may help you.\n\nIf possible, take these steps while waiting for medical help:\n\nMove far away from the snake.\nStay still and calm.\nRemove any jewelry, watches or tight clothing before swelling starts.\nSit or lie down so that the bite is in a neutral, comfortable position.\nClean the bite with soap and water. Cover or wrap it loosely with a clean, dry bandage.\n\nCaution\nDon\'t use a tourniquet or apply ice.\nDon\'t cut the bite or try to remove the venom.\nDon\'t drink caffeine or alcohol.\nDon\'t take pain-relieving medicine, such as aspirin, ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others) or naproxen sodium (Aleve). Doing so can increase your risk of bleeding.\nDon\'t try to catch or trap the snake. Try to remember its color and shape so that you can describe it. If possible, take a picture of the snake from a safe distance. Knowing what kind of snake bit you can help with treatment.</string>
    <string name="Snakebites_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Most snakebites happen on the arms, wrists or hands. Typical symptoms of a nonvenomous snakebite are pain, injury and scratches at the site of the bite.\n\nAfter a venomous snakebite, there usually is serious pain and tenderness at the site. This can worsen to swelling and bruising at the site that may move all the way up the arm or leg. Other symptoms are nausea, labored breathing and feelings of weakness, as well as an odd taste in the mouth.\n\nSome snakes, such as coral snakes, have toxins that affect the brain and nerves. This can cause symptoms such as upper eyelid drooping, tingling fingers or toes, difficulty swallowing, and muscle weakness.\n\nSometimes, a venomous snake can bite without injecting venom. This is called a dry bite.</string>
    <string name="Snakebites_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Most venomous snakes in North America have eyes like slits and are called pit vipers. Their heads are triangle-shaped and they have fangs. One exception is the coral snake, which has a cigar-shaped head and round pupils. Nonvenomous snakes typically have rounded heads, round pupils and no fangs.</string>
    <string name="Snakebites_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Snakebites_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="SpiderBites_term">Spider Bites</string>
    <string name="SpiderBites_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Most spider bites cause only minor injury. Bites from a few spider species can be dangerous.</string>
    <string name="SpiderBites_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek medical care right away if:\n\nYou were bitten by a dangerous spider, such as a black widow or a brown recluse.\nYou\'re unsure whether the bite was from a dangerous spider.\nYou have severe pain, stomach cramping or a growing wound at the bite site.\nYou\'re having problems breathing or swallowing.\nThe area of inflamed skin is spreading or has streaks.</string>
    <string name="SpiderBites_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Symptoms of a black widow spider bite can include:\n\nInflamed skin, pain and swelling.\nSevere stomach pain or cramping.\nNausea, vomiting, shaking or sweating.\n\nSymptoms of a brown recluse spider bite can include:\n\nAt first, a mild pain.\nFever, chills and body aches.\nA sore with a blue or purple center and a ring around it.</string>
    <string name="SpiderBites_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Black widow spiders\nYou can usually identify a black widow spider by the red hourglass marking on its belly. In the United States, this spider is more common in the South. It\'s also found in Europe.\n\nBrown recluse spider\nThe brown recluse spider has a violin-shaped marking on its back, but this mark can be hard to see. This spider is commonly found in the southern half of the United States and in South America, where it is known as the brown spider.</string>
    <string name="SpiderBites_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To take care of a spider bite:\n\nClean the wound with mild soap and water. Then apply an antibiotic ointment three times a day to help prevent infection.\nApply a cool cloth over the bite for 15 minutes each hour. Use a clean cloth dampened with water or filled with ice. This helps reduce pain and swelling.\nIf possible, raise the affected area.\nTake a nonprescription pain reliever as needed.\nIf the wound is itchy, an antihistamine might help. Examples are diphenhydramine or cetirizine. Or try calamine lotion or a steroid cream.\nFor pain and muscle spasms, your health care provider might prescribe pain medicine, muscle relaxants or both. You might also need a tetanus shot.</string>
    <string name="SpiderBites_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="SpinalInjury_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Get help. Call 911 or emergency medical help.\nKeep the person still. Place heavy towels or rolled sheets on both sides of the neck or hold the head and neck to prevent movement.\nAvoid moving the head or neck. Provide as much first aid as possible without moving the person\'s head or neck. If the person shows no signs of circulation (breathing, coughing or movement), begin CPR, but do not tilt the head back to open the airway. Use your fingers to gently grasp the jaw and lift it forward. If the person has no pulse, begin chest compressions.\nKeep helmet on. If the person is wearing a helmet, don\'t remove it. A football helmet facemask should be removed if you need to access the airway.\nDon\'t roll alone. If you must roll the person because he or she is vomiting, choking on blood or because you have to make sure the person is still breathing, you need at least one other person. With one of you at the head and another along the side of the injured person, work together to keep the person\'s head, neck and back aligned while rolling the person onto one side.</string>
    <string name="SpinalInjury_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Spinal Injury</string>
    <string name="SpinalInjury_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you suspect a back or neck (spinal) injury, do not move the affected person. Permanent paralysis and other serious complications can result. Assume a person has a spinal injury if:\n\nThere\'s evidence of a head injury with an ongoing change in the person\'s level of consciousness\nThe person complains of severe pain in his or her neck or back\nAn injury has exerted substantial force on the back or head\nThe person complains of weakness, numbness, or paralysis or lacks control of his or her limbs, bladder or bowels\nThe neck or body is twisted or positioned oddly</string>
    <string name="SpinalInjury_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Assume a person has a spinal injury if:\n\nThere\'s evidence of a head injury with an ongoing change in the person\'s level of consciousness\nThe person complains of severe pain in his or her neck or back\nAn injury has exerted substantial force on the back or head\nThe person complains of weakness, numbness, or paralysis or lacks control of his or her limbs, bladder or bowels\nThe neck or body is twisted or positioned oddly</string>
    <string name="SpinalInjury_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="SpinalInjury_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="SpinalInjury_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="Sprain_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Sprain</string>
    <string name="Sprain_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">A sprain is an injury to a ligament caused by stretching the ligament too far or tearing it. A ligament can tear partway or all the way. Ligaments are tough, elastic-like bands that connect bone to bone. They help hold joints in place.</string>
    <string name="Sprain_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek medical care right away if:\n\nYou can\'t put weight on the injured leg, the joint feels unstable or numb, or you can\'t use the joint. This may mean the ligament was completely torn. On the way to see your healthcare professional, apply a cold pack.\nYou have a change of color or streaks of color that spread out from the injured area. This may mean you have an infection.\nYou have pain directly over the bones of an injured joint.\nYou have re-injured an area that has been injured a few times in the past.\nYou have a severe sprain. Delayed treatment might lead to ongoing pain and the joint not being stable.</string>
    <string name="Sprain_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Areas of the body most likely to sprain are ankles, knees and wrists. Sprained ligaments often swell quickly, are painful and might cause bruising. Often, the greater the pain and swelling, the worse the injury is. For most minor sprains, you can start treatment yourself.</string>
    <string name="Sprain_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Sprain_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To treat a sprain, try the R.I.C.E. approach — rest, ice, compression, elevation:\n\nRest the injured area. Your healthcare professional may say not to put weight on the injured area for 48 to 72 hours. You may need to use crutches or not use the sprained area. A splint or brace also may be helpful at first.\n\nEven with an injury such as an ankle sprain, you can often exercise other muscles to keep from losing strength. For instance, you can use an exercise bicycle that has movable arm handles. This works your arms and the leg that isn\'t injured.\n\nYou can rest the injured ankle on the footrest. That way, you still can get a good workout while letting the ankle injury heal.\n\nIce the area. Use a cold pack, a bath of ice and water, or a compression sleeve filled with cold water to keep swelling down after an injury. Ice the area as soon as you can after the injury.\n\nIce the area for 15 to 20 minutes, 4 to 8 times a day, for the first 48 hours or until swelling goes down. Don\'t use ice for more than 20 minutes at a time. Use a dishcloth or thin towel between the ice and your skin. Putting ice right on the skin or icing for too long can damage tissue.\n\nCompress the area with an elastic wrap or bandage. Keeping pressure on the area might keep swelling down.\nElevate the injured area. Keep it raised on a pillow or cushion above your heart whenever possible. This helps keep swelling down.\nSprains can take days to months to heal. As the pain and swelling improve, gently begin using the injured area. It should get better over time. Pain relievers available without a prescription, such as ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others) and acetaminophen (Tylenol, others), might help ease pain.</string>
    <string name="Sprain_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">You must restore strength and stability to the injured area before you go back to sports or fitness activities. A physical therapist or other sports medicine professional can show you exercises to help you heal and help keep you from injuring the area again.</string>

    <string name="Sunburn_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If you have been sunburned, you will notice the signs and symptoms within a few hours after too much sun. The affected skin will be painful, inflamed and hot to the touch. Blisters might develop. You may also experience headache, fever or nausea.</string>
    <string name="Sunburn_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Seek immediate medical care if you are sunburned and experience:\n\nA fever over 103 degrees Fahrenheit (39.4 degrees Celsius) with vomiting\nConfusion\nAn infection in the sunburned area\nDehydration</string>
    <string name="Sunburn_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">The affected skin will be painful, inflamed and hot to the touch. Blisters might develop. You may also experience headache, fever or nausea.</string>
    <string name="Sunburn_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="Sunburn_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="StringFormatInvalid,UnusedResources">First aid might offer some relief from the discomfort of sunburn:\n\nTake a pain reliever such as ibuprofen (Advil, Motrin IB, others) or acetaminophen (Tylenol, others) as soon as possible after getting too much sun. Or try a gel pain reliever that you rub on the skin.\nCool the skin. Apply to the affected skin a clean towel dampened with cool tap water. Or take a cool bath with. Add about 2 ounces (60 grams) of baking soda to the tub. Cool the skin for about 10 minutes several times a day.\nApply a moisturizer, lotion or gel. An aloe vera lotion or gel or calamine lotion can be soothing. Try cooling the product in the refrigerator before applying. Avoid products that contain alcohol.\nDrink extra water for a day to help prevent dehydration.\nLeave blisters alone. An intact blister can help the skin heal. If a blister does break, trim off the dead skin with a clean, small scissors. Gently clean the area with mild soap and water. Then apply an antibiotic ointment to the wound and cover it with a nonstick bandage.\nProtect yourself from further sun exposure while your skin heals from the sunburn.\nApply a soothing medicated cream. For mild to moderate sunburn, apply nonprescription 1% hydrocortisone cream to the affected area three times a day for three days. Try cooling the product in the refrigerator before applying.\nTreat sunburned eyes by covering them with a clean towel dampened with cool tap water. Don\'t wear contacts until your eye symptoms have gone away. Don\'t rub your eyes.\nSeek medical care for large blisters or those that form on the face, hands or genitals. Also seek medical help if you have worsening pain, headache, confusion, nausea, fever, chills, eye pain or vision changes, or signs of infection, such as blisters with swelling, pus or streaks.</string>
    <string name="Sunburn_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />

    <string name="TickBites_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Most tick bites are painless and cause only minor signs and symptoms, such as a change in skin color, swelling or a sore on the skin.\n\nBut some ticks spread bacteria that cause illnesses, including Lyme disease and Rocky Mountain spotted fever. In general, to spread Lyme disease a tick needs to be attached to a person\'s skin for at least 36 hours. Other infections can be transferred in a few hours or even a few minutes.</string>
    <string name="TickBites_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Tick Bites</string>
    <string name="TickBites_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">To take care of a tick bite:\n\nRemove the tick promptly and carefully. Use fine-tipped forceps or tweezers to grasp the tick as close to the skin as possible. Gently pull out the tick using a slow and steady upward motion. Avoid twisting or squeezing the tick. Do not handle the tick with bare hands. Do not use petroleum jelly, fingernail polish or a hot match to remove a tick.\nSecure the tick and take a picture. A picture of the tick can help you and your health care provider identify what type it is and whether you are at risk of a transmitted disease. You can trap the tick in a piece of tape for disposal in the garbage. Your provider may want to see the tick or a photo if you develop new symptoms.\nWash your hands and the bite site. Use warm water and soap, rubbing alcohol, or an iodine scrub.</string>
    <string name="TickBites_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call 911 or your local emergency number if you develop:\n\nA severe headache\nDifficulty breathing\nParalysis\nHeart palpitations</string>
    <string name="TickBites_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="TickBites_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Contact your healthcare professional if:\n\nYou aren\'t able to completely remove the tick. The longer the tick remains attached to the skin, the greater the risk of getting a disease from it. Your skin may also get irritated.\nThe rash gets bigger. A small bump may appear at the site of the tick bite. This is typical. If it develops into a larger rash or you develop a rash anywhere, possibly with a bull\'s-eye pattern, it may be a sign of Lyme disease. The rash usually appears within 3 to 14 days.\n\nConsult your provider even if the rash disappears because you may still be at risk of having the disease. Your risk of contracting a disease from a tick bite depends on where you live or travel to, how much time you spend outside in woody and grassy areas, and how well you protect yourself.\n\nYou develop flu-like signs and symptoms. Fever, chills, fatigue, muscle and joint pain, and a headache may accompany the rash.\nYou think the bite site is infected. Signs and symptoms include pain, change in skin color or oozing from the site.\nYou think you were bitten by a deer tick. You may need antibiotics.\nIf possible, bring the tick, or a photo of the tick, with you to your doctor\'s appointment.</string>
    <string name="TickBites_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">If possible, bring the tick, or a photo of the tick, with you to your doctor\'s appointment.</string>

    <string name="ToothLoss_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ToothLoss_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ToothLoss_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ToothLoss_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources" />
    <string name="ToothLoss_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">It\'s sometimes possible to successfully implant permanent teeth that have been knocked out, but only if you follow the steps below immediately — before you see a dentist.\n\nHandle your tooth by the top or crown only — don\'t touch the roots.\nInspect the crown and root to determine if any portion of either appears to be missing or fractured.\nDon\'t rub the tooth or scrape it to remove debris. This damages the root surface, making the tooth less likely to survive.\nIf your tooth has dirt or foreign material on it, gently rinse your tooth briefly — no more than 10 seconds — in a bowl of lukewarm tap water to remove the debris. Don\'t hold it under running water, because too much tap water could kill the cells on the root surface that help reattach the tooth.\nTry to put your tooth back in the socket. If it doesn\'t go all the way into place, bite down slowly and gently on gauze or a moistened paper towel to help keep it in place. Hold the tooth in place until you see your dentist.\nIf you can\'t put your tooth back in the socket, immediately place it between your cheek and gum, or in cold milk or your own saliva. Or use an over-the-counter product that preserves a knocked-out tooth, such as those approved by the American Dental Association, if you have quick access to it.\nGet emergency dental care. If your dentist\'s office isn\'t open, go to the emergency room.</string>
    <string name="ToothLoss_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Baby teeth (primary teeth) are not implanted if they\'re knocked out.\n\nFor permanent teeth, if a sharp surface or shiny surface is apparent, there\'s a chance that part of the root is still in the socket, and reimplantation becomes less successful. If reimplantation doesn\'t occur within two hours after the tooth is knocked out — sooner is better — the likelihood of success becomes poor. So it\'s vital to get emergency dental care.</string>
    <string name="Toothache_overview" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Tooth decay is the primary cause of toothaches for most children and adults. Bacteria that live in your mouth thrive on the sugars and starches in the food you eat. These bacteria form a sticky plaque that clings to the surface of your teeth.\n\nAcids produced by the bacteria in plaque can eat through the hard, white coating on the outside of your teeth (enamel), creating a cavity. The first sign of decay may be a sensation of pain when you eat something sweet, very cold or very hot. Sometimes decay will show as a brown or white spot on the tooth.</string>

    <string name="Toothache_term" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Toothache</string>
    <string name="Toothache_symptoms" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">An accumulation of food and debris between your teeth, especially if your teeth have spaces between them\nInflammation or infection at the root of the tooth or in the gums\nTrauma to the tooth, including injury or grinding your teeth\nSudden fracture of the tooth or tooth root\nA split in the tooth that occurs over time\nTeeth that start to appear (erupt) through the gums, such as with teething or wisdom teeth that don\'t have enough room to emerge or develop normally (impacted wisdom teeth)\nA sinus infection that can be felt as pain in the teeth</string>
    <string name="Toothache_immediate_actions" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Call your dentist immediately if you have any of the following with a toothache:\n\nPain that persists for more than a day or two\nFever\nSigns and symptoms of infection, such as swelling, pain when you bite, red gums or a foul-tasting discharge\nTrouble breathing or swallowing</string>
    <string name="Toothache_common_triggers_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Other causes of a toothache can include:\n\nAn accumulation of food and debris between your teeth, especially if your teeth have spaces between them\nInflammation or infection at the root of the tooth or in the gums\nTrauma to the tooth, including injury or grinding your teeth\nSudden fracture of the tooth or tooth root\nA split in the tooth that occurs over time\nTeeth that start to appear (erupt) through the gums, such as with teething or wisdom teeth that don\'t have enough room to emerge or develop normally (impacted wisdom teeth)\nA sinus infection that can be felt as pain in the teeth</string>
    <string name="Toothache_treatment_and_aftercare_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Until you can see your dentist, try these self-care tips for a toothache:\n\nRinse your mouth with warm water.\nUse dental floss to remove any food particles or plaque wedged between your teeth.\nConsider taking an over-the-counter (OTC) pain reliever to dull the ache, but don\'t place aspirin or another painkiller directly against your gums because it may burn your gum tissue.\nIf the toothache is caused by trauma to the tooth, apply a cold compress to the outside of your cheek.</string>
    <string name="Toothache_prevention_and_preparedness_text" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Use caution with products containing benzocaine\nPrevious advice included sparingly applying an OTC antiseptic containing benzocaine directly to the irritated tooth and gum for temporary relief. But benzocaine has been linked to a rare and serious, sometimes deadly, condition called methemoglobinemia, which decreases the amount of oxygen that the blood can carry. So follow these guidelines:\n\nTalk to your dentist or doctor before using an OTC antiseptic containing benzocaine.\nDon\'t use any products that contain benzocaine — such as teething gels with benzocaine (Anbesol, Orabase, Orajel, others) — in children younger than 2 years old.\nNever use more than the recommended dose of benzocaine.\nStore products containing benzocaine out of the reach of children.</string>
    <string name="poison_control">POISON CONTROL</string>
    <string name="image_desc">Image showing details about the selected first aid topic</string>
    <string name="disclaimer_text">All information and images were sourced from the Mayo Clinic\'s official website.</string>
    <string name="disclaimer_full_text">All information and images were sourced from the Mayo Clinic\'s official website. Disclaimer: This information is not intended as a substitute for professional medical advice, emergency treatment or formal first-aid training. Don\'t use this information to diagnose or develop a treatment plan for a health problem or disease without consulting a qualified health care provider. If you\'re in a life-threatening or emergency medical situation, seek medical assistance immediately.</string>
    <string name="disclaimer_checkbox">Got it, do not show me this again</string>
    <string name="disclaimer_button_ok">Okay</string>
    <string name="learn_cpr" tools:ignore="UnusedResources">Learn CPR</string>
    <string name="cardiopulmonary_resuscitation_cpr">Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation (CPR)</string>
    <string name="cpr_intro">Cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) is a lifesaving technique that\'s useful in many emergencies in which someone\'s breathing or heartbeat has stopped. For example, when someone has a heart attack or nearly drowns. The American Heart Association recommends starting CPR with hard and fast chest compressions. This hands-only CPR recommendation applies to both untrained bystanders and first responders.\n\nIf you\'re afraid to do CPR or unsure how to perform CPR correctly, know that it\'s always better to try than to do nothing at all. The difference between doing something and doing nothing could be someone\'s life.\n\nHere\'s advice from the American Heart Association:\n\nUntrained. If you\'re not trained in CPR or worried about giving rescue breaths, then provide hands-only CPR. That means uninterrupted chest compressions of 100 to 120 a minute until paramedics arrive (described in more detail below). You don\'t need to try rescue breathing.\nTrained and ready to go. If you\'re well-trained and confident in your ability, check to see if there is a pulse and breathing. If there is no pulse or breathing within 10 seconds, begin chest compressions. Start CPR with 30 chest compressions before giving two rescue breaths.\nTrained but rusty. If you\'ve previously received CPR training but you\'re not confident in your abilities, then just do chest compressions at a rate of 100 to 120 a minute. Details are described below.\nThe above advice applies to situations in which adults, children and infants need CPR, but not newborns. Newborns are babies up to 4 weeks old.\n\nCPR can keep oxygen-rich blood flowing to the brain and other organs until emergency medical treatment can restore a typical heart rhythm. When the heart stops, the body no longer gets oxygen-rich blood. The lack of oxygen-rich blood can cause brain damage in only a few minutes.\n\nIf you are untrained and have immediate access to a phone, call 911 or your local emergency number before beginning CPR. The dispatcher can tell you how to do the proper procedures until help arrives. To learn CPR properly, take an accredited first-aid training course, including CPR and how to use an automated external defibrillator (AED).\n\nBefore you begin\nBefore starting CPR, check:\n\nIs the environment safe for the person?\nIs the person conscious or unconscious?\nIf the person appears unconscious, tap or shake their shoulder and ask loudly, \"Are you OK?\"\nIf the person doesn\'t respond and you\'re with another person who can help, have one person call 911 or the local emergency number and get the AED, if one is available. Have the other person begin CPR.\nIf you are alone and have immediate access to a telephone, call 911 or your local emergency number before beginning CPR. Get the AED if one is available.\nAs soon as an AED is available, deliver one shock if instructed by the device, then begin CPR.\nRemember to spell C-A-B\nThe American Heart Association uses the letters C-A-B to help people remember the order to perform the steps of CPR.\n\nC: compressions\nA: airway\nB: breathing</string>
    <string name="cpr_chest_compressions_info">Compressions means you use your hands to push down hard and fast in a specific way on the person\'s chest. Compressions are the most important step in CPR. Follow these steps for performing CPR compressions:\n\nPut the person on their back on a firm surface.\nKneel next to the person\'s neck and shoulders.\nPlace the lower palm of your hand over the center of the person\'s chest, between the nipples.\nPlace your other hand on top of the first hand. Keep your elbows straight. Place your shoulders directly above your hands.\nPush straight down on the chest at least 2 inches (5 centimeters) but no more than 2.4 inches (6 centimeters). Use your entire body weight, not just your arms, when doing compressions.\nPush hard at a rate of 100 to 120 compressions a minute. The American Heart Association suggests performing compressions to the beat of the song \"Stayin\' Alive.\" Allow the chest to spring back after each push.\nIf you haven\'t been trained in CPR, continue chest compressions until there are signs of movement or until emergency medical personnel take over. If you have been trained in CPR, go on to opening the airway and rescue breathing.</string>
    <string name="cpr_chest_compressions">Compressions: Restore blood flow</string>
    <string name="cpr_open_airway">Airway: Open the Airway</string>
    <string name="cpr_airway_info">If you\'re trained in CPR and you\'ve performed 30 chest compressions, open the person\'s airway using the head-tilt, chin-lift maneuver. Put your palm on the person\'s forehead and gently tilt the head back. Then with the other hand, gently lift the chin forward to open the airway.</string>
    <string name="cpr_rescue_breathing">Breathing: Breathe for the person</string>
    <string name="cpr_rescue_breathing_info">Rescue breathing can be mouth-to-mouth breathing or mouth-to-nose breathing if the mouth is seriously injured or can\'t be opened. Current recommendations suggest performing rescue breathing using a bag-mask device with a high-efficiency particulate air (HEPA) filter.\n\nAfter opening the airway (using the head-tilt, chin-lift maneuver), pinch the nostrils shut for mouth-to-mouth breathing and cover the person\'s mouth with yours, making a seal.\nPrepare to give two rescue breaths. Give the first rescue breath — lasting one second — and watch to see if the chest rises.\nIf the chest rises, give a second breath.\nIf the chest doesn\'t rise, repeat the head-tilt, chin-lift maneuver and then give a second breath. Thirty chest compressions followed by two rescue breaths is considered one cycle. Be careful not to provide too many breaths or to breathe with too much force.\nContinue chest compressions to restore blood flow.\nAs soon as an automated external defibrillator (AED) is available, apply it and follow the prompts. Give one shock, then continue chest compressions for two more minutes before giving a second shock. If you\'re not trained to use an AED, a 911 operator or another emergency medical operator may be able to give you instructions. If an AED isn\'t available, go to step 5 below.\nContinue CPR until there are signs of movement or emergency medical personnel take over.</string>
    <string name="Resources">Resources</string>
    <string name="first_aid_kit_info">A well-stocked first-aid kit can help you respond effectively to common injuries and emergencies. Keep at least one first-aid kit in your home and one in your car. Store your kits someplace easy to get to and out of the reach of young children. Make sure children old enough to understand the purpose of the kits know where they\'re stored.\n\nYou can buy first-aid kits at many drugstores or assemble your own. You may want to tailor your kit based on your activities and needs.\n\nCheck your first-aid kits regularly to be sure the flashlight batteries work and to replace supplies that have expired or been used up.\n\nConsider taking a first-aid course through the American Red Cross. Contact your local chapter for information on classes.\n\nPrepare children for medical emergencies in age-appropriate ways. The American Red Cross offers a number of helpful resources, including classes designed to help children understand and use first-aid techniques.</string>
    <string name="item_name">Item Name</string>
    <string name="emergency_essentials_info">Emergency essentials kits can help you respond to natural disasters or other serious situations. Prepare for the unexpected by putting together a survival kit that could be useful if you needed to evacuate your home. Pack enough supplies to last three days, and keep your emergency essentials handy. Make sure your family members know where to find the kit. Consider keeping basic emergency essentials in your car as well.\nA basic emergency essentials kit includes:</string>
</resources>